<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Movies tag represents a list of movies -->
<movies xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="moviesSchema.xsd">
	<movie id="ID-1" title="Harry Potter And The Philosopher Stone" genre="Fantasy" release_date="2002-02-01" duration="152" rating="PG">
		<plot>	
				Late one night, Albus Dumbledore and Minerva McGonagall, professors at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, along with groundskeeper Rubeus Hagrid, deliver an orphaned infant wizard named Harry Potter to his Muggle aunt and uncle, Petunia and Vernon Dursley, his only living relatives.
				Ten years later, just before Harry's eleventh birthday, owls begin delivering letters addressed to him. When the abusive Dursleys adamantly refuse to allow Harry to open any and flee to an island hut, Hagrid arrives to personally deliver Harry's letter of acceptance to Hogwarts. Hagrid also reveals that Harry's parents, James and Lily, were killed by a dark wizard named Lord Voldemort. The killing curse that Voldemort had cast towards Harry rebounded, destroying Voldemort's body and giving Harry his lightning-bolt scar. Hagrid then takes Harry to Diagon Alley for school supplies and gives him a pet snowy owl whom he names Hedwig. Harry buys a wand that is connected to Voldemort's own wand.
				At King's Cross station, Harry boards the Hogwarts Express train, and meets fellow students Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger during the journey. Arriving at Hogwarts, Harry also meets Draco Malfoy, who is from a wealthy wizard family; the two immediately form a rivalry. The students assemble in the Great Hall where the Sorting Hat sorts the first-years into four respective houses: Gryffindor, Hufflepuff, Ravenclaw, and Slytherin. Harry is placed into Gryffindor alongside Ron and Hermione, while Draco is placed into Slytherin, a house noted for dark wizards.
				As he studies magic, Harry learns more about his parents and Voldemort, and his natural talent for broomstick flying gets him recruited for the Gryffindor Quidditch team as the youngest Seeker in a century. While returning to the Gryffindor common room, the staircases change paths, leading Harry, Ron and Hermione to the third floor, which is forbidden to students. There they discover a giant three-headed dog named Fluffy. On Halloween, Ron insults Hermione after she shows off in Charms class; upset, she spends the entire afternoon crying in the girls' bathroom. That evening, a giant marauding troll enters it, but Harry and Ron save Hermione, and they make up and become close friends after Hermione takes the blame for the incident by claiming she went looking for the troll.
				The trio discover that Fluffy is guarding the philosopher's stone, a magical object that can turn metal into gold and produce an immortality elixir. Harry suspects that Potions teacher and head of Slytherin House, Severus Snape, wants the stone to return Voldemort to physical form. When Hagrid accidentally reveals that music puts Fluffy asleep, Harry, Ron and Hermione decide to find the stone before Snape. Fluffy is already asleep, but the trio face other barriers, including a deadly plant called Devil's Snare, a room filled with aggressive flying keys, and a giant chess game that knocks out Ron.
				After overcoming the barriers, Harry encounters Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher Quirinus Quirrell who wants the stone; Snape had figured it out and had been protecting Harry. Quirrell removes his turban to reveal a weakened Voldemort living on the back of his head. Dumbledore's protective enchantment places the stone in Harry's possession. Voldemort attempts to bargain the stone from Harry in exchange for resurrecting his parents, but Harry sees through his trick and refuses. Quirrell attempts to kill Harry. When Harry touches Quirrell's skin, it burns Quirrell, reducing him to ashes. Voldemort's soul rises from the pile and escapes, knocking out Harry as it passes through him.
				Harry recovers in the school infirmary. Dumbledore tells him the stone has been destroyed to prevent misuse, and that Ron and Hermione are safe. He also reveals how Harry defeated Quirrell: when Lily died to save Harry, a love-based protection against Voldemort was placed on him. At the end-of-school-year feast, Harry, Ron, and Hermione are rewarded extra house points for their heroism, tying Gryffindor for first place with Slytherin; Dumbledore then awards ten points to their housemate Neville Longbottom for having had the courage to stand up to the trio, granting Gryffindor the House Cup. Harry returns to the Dursleys for the summer, happy to finally have a real home at Hogwarts. 
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Heyday Films</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>1492 Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>125000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>Northumberland, County Durham,  North Yorkshire, London, Hertfordshire, Wiltshire</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Chris Colombus</name>
				<biography>	
							Chris Joseph Columbus(born September 10, 1958) is an American filmmaker. Born in Spangler, Pennsylvania, Columbus studied film at Tisch School of the Arts where he developed an interest in filmmaking. After writing screenplays for several teen comedies in the mid-1980s, he made his directorial debut with a teen adventure, Adventures in Babysitting (1987). Columbus gained recognition soon after with the highly successful Christmas comedy Home Alone (1990) and its sequel Home Alone 2: Lost in New York (1992).
							The comedy Mrs. Doubtfire (1993), starring Robin Williams, was another box office success for Columbus. He went on to direct several other films throughout the 1990s, which were mostly met with lukewarm reception. However, he found commercial success again for directing the film adaptations of J. K. Rowling's novels, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (2001) and its sequel, Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (2002), which are his highest-grossing films to date. In addition to directing, Columbus was a producer for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (2004), and the drama The Help (2011). He also directed the fantasy Percy Jackson and the Olympians: The Lightning Thief (2010) and the 3D action comedy Pixels (2015).
							Columbus is the co-founder of 1492 Pictures, a film production company that has produced some of his films since 1995. More recently, he co-founded another production firm with his daughter in 2014, called Maiden Voyage Pictures. In 2017, he launched ZAG Animation Studios, alongside Michael Barnathan, Haim Saban, and Jeremy Zag. Columbus is also known for his collaboration with composer John Williams, with whom he had worked on the films Home Alone and Harry Potter. 
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Steve Kloves</name>
				<biography>Stephen Keith Kloves(born March 18, 1960) is an American filmmaker. He wrote and directed the 1989 film The Fabulous Baker Boys and is mainly known for his adaptations of novels, especially for all but one of the Harry Potter films (the exception being Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix) and for Wonder Boys, for which he was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay. </biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Joanne Kathleen Rowling</name>
				<biography>	
							Joanne Rowling CH OBE FRSL (born 31 July 1965), best known by her pen name J. K. Rowling, is a British author and philanthropist. She wrote Harry Potter, a seven-volume fantasy series published from 1997 to 2007. The series has sold over 600 million copies, been translated into 84 languages, and spawned a global media franchise including films and video games. The Casual Vacancy (2012) was her first novel for adults. She writes Cormoran Strike, an ongoing crime fiction series, under the alias Robert Galbraith.
							Born in Yate, Gloucestershire, Rowling was working as a researcher and bilingual secretary for Amnesty International in 1990 when she conceived the idea for the Harry Potter series while on a delayed train from Manchester to London. The seven-year period that followed saw the death of her mother, the birth of her first child, divorce from her first husband, and relative poverty until the first novel in the series, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, was published in 1997. Six sequels followed, and by 2008, Forbes had named her the world's highest-paid author.
							Rowling concluded the Harry Potter series with Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows (2007). The novels follow a boy called Harry Potter as he attends Hogwarts (a school for wizards), and battles Lord Voldemort. Death and the divide between good and evil are the central themes of the series. Its influences include Bildungsroman (the coming-of-age genre), school stories, fairy tales, and Christian allegory. The series revived fantasy as a genre in the children's market, spawned a host of imitators, and inspired an active fandom. Critical reception has been more mixed. Many reviewers see Rowling's writing as conventional; some regard her portrayal of gender and social division as regressive. There were also religious debates over the Harry Potter series.
							Rowling has won many accolades for her work. She has received an OBE and made a Companion of Honour for services to literature and philanthropy. Harry Potter brought her wealth and recognition, which she has used to advance philanthropic endeavours and political causes. She co-founded the charity Lumos and established the Volant Charitable Trust, named after her mother. Rowling's charitable giving centres on medical causes and supporting at-risk women and children. In politics, she has donated to Britain's Labour Party and opposed Scottish independence and Brexit. She has publicly expressed her opinions on transgender people and related civil rights since 2017. These have been criticised as transphobic by LGBT rights organisations and some feminists, but have received support from other feminists and individuals.  
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Heyman</name>
				<biography>David Jonathan Heyman (born 26 July 1961) is a British film producer and the founder of Heyday Films. Heyman is best known as the primary producer of all eight installments of the Harry Potter film series, which are based on a series of popular fantasy novels of the same name by author J. K. Rowling. He then produced all three installments of its spin-off prequel series, Fantastic Beasts. His work makes him the second-most commercially successful producer of all time.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>John Williams</name>
				<biography>	
							John Towner Williams (born February 8, 1932) is an American composer, conductor, and pianist. In a career that has spanned seven decades, he has composed some of the most popular, recognizable and critically acclaimed film scores in cinema history. Williams has won 25 Grammy Awards, five Academy Awards, seven British Academy Film Awards, and four Golden Globe Awards. With 53 Academy Award nominations, he is the second most-nominated individual, after only Walt Disney. His compositions are considered the epitome of film music, and he is considered among the greatest composers in the history of cinema.Williams has composed many of his film scoring works for frequent collaborators Steven Spielberg and George Lucas, and other directors such as Chris Columbus, Oliver Stone, Richard Donner, Irvin Kershner, Sydney Pollack, Alfred Hitchcock, Mark Rydell, Mark Robson, Jean-Jacques Annaud, Robert Altman, and J. J. Abrams. He has a very distinct and recognizable sound that mixes romanticism, impressionism and atonal music with complex orchestration.
							Williams has been associated with director Steven Spielberg since 1974, composing music for all but five of his feature films, and George Lucas, with whom he has worked on both of his main franchises, Star Wars and Indiana Jones. His early work as a film composer includes The Killers (1964), How to Steal a Million (1966), Valley of the Dolls (1967), and Goodbye Mr. Chips (1969). He has received five Academy Awards for Best Original Score for his work on Fiddler on the Roof (1971), Jaws (1975), Star Wars (1977), E.T.: The Extra Terrestrial (1982), and Schindler's List (1993). Williams has composed for many popular films including the Star Wars saga, Superman, the first two Home Alone films, the Indiana Jones films, the first two Jurassic Park films, and the first three Harry Potter films. Other memorable film scores from his collaboration with Spielberg include Close Encounters of the Third Kind (1977), Hook (1991), Saving Private Ryan (1998), Catch Me If You Can (2002), War of the Worlds (2005), War Horse (2011), Lincoln (2012), and The Fabelmans (2022).
							Williams has also composed numerous classical concertos and other works for orchestral ensembles and solo instruments. He served as the Boston Pops' principal conductor from 1980 to 1993 and is its laureate conductor.Other works by Williams include theme music for the 1984 Summer Olympic Games, NBC Sunday Night Football, "The Mission" theme used by NBC News and Seven News in Australia, the television series Lost in Space and Land of the Giants, and the incidental music for the first season of Gilligan's Island. Williams announced but then rescinded his intention to retire from film score composing after the release of Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny in 2023.
							In 2005, the American Film Institute selected Williams's score to 1977's Star Wars as the greatest film score of all time. The Library of Congress entered the Star Wars soundtrack into the National Recording Registry for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant". Williams was inducted into the Hollywood Bowl's Hall of Fame in 2000, and he received a Kennedy Center Honor in 2004. His AFI Life Achievement Award in 2016 was the first to be awarded outside of the acting and directing fields. He has composed the score for nine of the top 25 highest-grossing films at the U.S. box office (adjusted for inflation). His work has influenced other composers of film, popular, and contemporary classical music.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Daniel Radcliffe</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Harry Potter</character>
					<character_description>An 11-year-old orphan living with his unwelcoming aunt, uncle, and cousin, who learns of his own fame as a wizard known to have survived his parents' murder at the hands of the dark wizard Lord Voldemort as an infant when he is accepted to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. Columbus had wanted Radcliffe for the role since he saw him in the BBC's production of David Copperfield, before the open casting sessions had taken place, but had been told by casting director Susan Figgis that Radcliffe's protective parents would not allow their son to take the part. Columbus explained that his persistence in giving Radcliffe the role was responsible for Figgis' resignation. Radcliffe was asked to audition in 2000, when Heyman and Kloves met him and his parents at a production of Stones in His Pockets in London. Heyman and Columbus successfully managed to convince Radcliffe's parents that their son would be protected from media intrusion, and they agreed to let him play Harry. Rowling approved of Radcliffe's casting, stating that "having seen his screen test I don't think Chris Columbus could have found a better Harry." Radcliffe was reportedly paid £1 million for the film, although he felt the fee was "not that important" to him. The Saunders triplets appear as Harry as a baby.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Emma Watson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Hermione Granger</character>
					<character_description>Harry's other best friend and the trio's brains. Watson's Oxford theatre teacher passed her name on to the casting agents and she had to do over five interviews before she got the part. Watson took her audition seriously, but "never really thought she had any chance of getting the role." The producers were impressed by Watson's self-confidence and she outperformed the thousands of other girls who had applied.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Rupert Grint</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Ron Wealsey</character>
					<character_description>Harry's best friend at Hogwarts and a younger member of the Weasley wizarding family. A fan of the series, Grint decided he would be perfect for the part "because he has ginger hair". Having seen a Newsround report about the open casting he sent in a video of himself rapping about how he wished to receive the part. His attempt was successful as the casting team asked for a meeting with him.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian Hart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Professor Quirrell</character>
					<character_description>The stuttering Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian Hart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Lord Voldemort</character>
					<character_description>Voldemort, an anagrammatic sobriquet for Tom Marvolo Riddle, is the archenemy of Harry Potter, who according to a prophecy has "the power to vanquish the Dark Lord". He attempts to murder the boy, but instead kills his parents, Lily and James Potter, and leaves Harry with a scar on his forehead in the shape of a lightning bolt. Nearly every witch or wizard dares not utter his name and refers to him instead with such monikers as "You-Know-Who", "He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named", or "The Dark Lord". Voldemort's obsession with blood purity signifies his aim to rid the wizarding world of Muggle (non-magical) heritage and to conquer both worlds, Muggle and wizarding, to achieve pure-blood dominance. Through his mother's family, he is the last descendant of the wizard Salazar Slytherin, one of the four founders of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. He is the leader of the Death Eaters, a group of evil wizards and witches dedicated to ridding the Wizarding World of Muggles and establishing Voldemort as its supreme ruler. </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Alan Rickman</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Severus Snape</character>
					<character_description>The Potions Master and head of Slytherin House.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Richard Harris</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Albus Dumbledore</character>
					<character_description>Hogwarts' Headmaster and one of the most famous and powerful wizards of all time. Harris initially rejected the role, only to reverse his decision after his granddaughter stated she would never speak to him again if he did not take it.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Tom Felton</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Draco Malfoy</character>
					<character_description>A student in Slytherin and Harry's rival.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard Francis-Bruce</name>
				<biography>Richard Leslie Francis-Bruce AM (born 10 December 1948) is an Australian film editor who has received several nominations for the Academy Award for Best Film Editing. </biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>John A. Midgley</name>
				<biography>John Midgley is an English sound engineer. He won an Oscar in the category Best Sound Mixing for Hugo and has been nominated for another two. He has worked on more than 100 films since 1977.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company>
					<name>Peacock</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Prime Video</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Max</name>
				</company>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.8</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.6</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>81</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>1024254401</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
<movie id="ID-2" title="Green Mile" genre="Drama" release_date="1999-12-10" duration="189" rating="PG">
		<plot>
				At a Louisiana assisted-living home in 1999, retiree Paul Edgecomb begins to cry while watching the film Top Hat. His companion Elaine becomes concerned, and Paul explains to her that the film reminded him of events that he witnessed when he was an officer at Cold Mountain Penitentiary's death row, nicknamed "The Green Mile".
				In 1935, Paul supervised Corrections Officers Brutus "Brutal" Howell, Dean Stanton, Harry Terwilliger, and Percy Wetmore, reporting to Warden Hal Moores. Percy, the nephew of the state governor's wife, demonstrates a severe sadistic streak but flaunts his family connections to avoid being held accountable. He is particularly abusive towards prisoner Eduard "Del" Delacroix, breaking his fingers and killing his pet mouse, Mr. Jingles.
				Paul is introduced to John Coffey, a physically imposing but mild-mannered black man sentenced to death after being convicted of raping and murdering two young white girls. He joins Del and another condemned convict: Arlen Bitterbuck, the first to be executed. The officers are forced to deal with psychotic new inmate William "Wild Bill" Wharton, who frequently causes trouble by assaulting the officers and racially abusing John, forcing them to restrain him in the block's padded cell on more than one occasion.
				After John heals Paul's severe bladder infection by touching him, and later resurrects Mr. Jingles, Paul gradually realizes that John possesses a supernatural ability to heal others. Paul doubts whether someone with the power to perform divine miracles is truly guilty of the crime.
				In exchange for resigning from the penitentiary and accepting a job at an insane asylum, Percy is allowed to oversee Del's execution. At the execution, Percy deliberately avoids soaking the sponge used to conduct electricity to Del's head, leading to Del suffering a gruesome and agonizing death by burning, with John forced to feel Del's pain as well. Paul and the other officers punish Percy by forcing him to spend a night in the padded cell. While Percy is locked away, they drug Wharton and secretly smuggle John out of the prison so that he can use his powers to heal Warden Moores' wife Melinda of a brain tumor, saving her life. After Percy is released from the padded room, the others threaten to report him for his various acts of misconduct if his behavior continues.
				John uses his powers to "release" Melinda's affliction into Percy's brain, causing Percy to shoot Wharton dead. Soon after, John reveals in a vision to Paul that Wharton was the true culprit of the crimes for which he was wrongfully condemned, releasing his supernatural energy into Paul in the process. Having gone into a catatonic state, Percy is committed to the same insane asylum where he had planned to work after resigning from the prison.
				After realizing that John is innocent, Paul becomes distraught at the thought of executing him and offers to let him go free. John tells Paul that the execution would be an act of mercy, as he views the world as a cruel place and is in constant pain from the suffering that people inflict upon each other. Mentioning that he has never seen a movie before, John watches Top Hat with the other officers as his last request. As John is taken to be executed, he is mercilessly scorned by the parents of the two girls who still believe him to be guilty. He asks not to have a hood placed over his head as he is afraid of the dark. Paul, Brutal, and the officers watch in great sadness, visibly holding back tears as John is executed.
				Back in present day, Paul tells Elaine that John's execution was the last that he and Brutal witnessed, as they both subsequently resigned from the prison and took jobs in the juvenile system. Paul reveals to Elaine that Mr. Jingles is still alive, having been blessed with a supernaturally long life thanks to John's healing touch. He also reveals that he is now 108 years old; he was 44 when John was executed. While Elaine sees Paul's long life as another of John's miracles, Paul speculates that he may have been condemned to linger on Earth and outlive all of his loved ones as a divine punishment for John's execution. Paul later attends Elaine's funeral and muses on how much longer he has left to live, saying, "We each owe a death. There are no exceptions. But, oh, God... sometimes, the Green Mile seems so long."
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company>
					<name>Castle Rock Entertainment </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Darkwoods Productions</name>
				</company>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>60000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>United States</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>	
					Frank Árpád Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959) is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007).
					Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).	
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>Frank Árpád Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959) is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007). Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>Frank Árpád Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959)[2] is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007).Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Valdes</name>
				<biography>David Valdes (born August 12, 1950, in Los Angeles) is an American film producer known for working in the western genre and collaborating with Clint Eastwood. His first production experience was as a guest on a film called Diary of a Mad Housewife, which was shot in his hometown in 1969.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Thomas Newman</name>
				<biography>	
					Thomas Montgomery Newman (born October 20, 1955) is an American composer and conductor best known for his many film scores. In a career that has spanned over four decades, he has scored numerous films including The Player (1992), The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Horse Whisperer (1998), American Beauty and The Green Mile (both 1999), In the Bedroom (2001), Road to Perdition and White Oleander (both 2002), Finding Nemo (2003), Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events (2004), Cinderella Man (2005), WALL-E (2008), the James Bond films Skyfall (2012) and Spectre (2015), Finding Dory (2016), 1917 (2019), and Elemental (2023). He also composed the music for the 2003 HBO miniseries Angels in America. Throughout his career, he has collaborated extensively with directors such as Sam Mendes, Andrew Stanton, Frank Darabont, Steven Soderbergh, Jon Avnet, John Madden and John Lee Hancock.
					Newman has been nominated for fifteen Academy Awards, tying him with fellow composer Alex North for the most nominations without a win. He has also been nominated for four Golden Globes, and has won two BAFTAs, six Grammys and an Emmy Award. Newman was honored with the Richard Kirk award at the 2000 BMI Film and TV Awards. The award is given annually to a composer who has made significant contributions to film and television music.[1] His achievements have contributed to the Newmans being the most nominated Academy Award extended family, with a collective 92 nominations in various music categories.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Tom Hanks</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Paul Edgecomb</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>David Morse</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Brutus Howell</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Michael Clarke Duncan</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>John Coffey</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Sam Rockwell</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Wild Bill</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Patricia Clarkson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Melinda Moores</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Bonnie Hunt</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Jan Engecomb</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard Francis-Bruce</name>
				<biography>Richard Leslie Francis-Bruce AM (born 10 December 1948) is an Australian film editor who has received several nominations for the Academy Award for Best Film Editing. </biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Robert J. Litt</name>
				<biography> </biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.0</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>8.6</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>79</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>286800000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
</movies>
