<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Movies tag represents a list of movies -->
<movies xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="moviesSchema.xsd">
	<movie id="ID-1" title="Harry Potter And The Philosopher Stone" genre="Fantasy" release_date="2002-02-01" duration="152" rating="PG">
		<plot>	
				Late one night, Albus Dumbledore and Minerva McGonagall, professors at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, along with groundskeeper Rubeus Hagrid, deliver an orphaned infant wizard named Harry Potter to his Muggle aunt and uncle, Petunia and Vernon Dursley, his only living relatives.
				Ten years later, just before Harry's eleventh birthday, owls begin delivering letters addressed to him. When the abusive Dursleys adamantly refuse to allow Harry to open any and flee to an island hut, Hagrid arrives to personally deliver Harry's letter of acceptance to Hogwarts. Hagrid also reveals that Harry's parents, James and Lily, were killed by a dark wizard named Lord Voldemort. The killing curse that Voldemort had cast towards Harry rebounded, destroying Voldemort's body and giving Harry his lightning-bolt scar. Hagrid then takes Harry to Diagon Alley for school supplies and gives him a pet snowy owl whom he names Hedwig. Harry buys a wand that is connected to Voldemort's own wand.
				At King's Cross station, Harry boards the Hogwarts Express train, and meets fellow students Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger during the journey. Arriving at Hogwarts, Harry also meets Draco Malfoy, who is from a wealthy wizard family; the two immediately form a rivalry. The students assemble in the Great Hall where the Sorting Hat sorts the first-years into four respective houses: Gryffindor, Hufflepuff, Ravenclaw, and Slytherin. Harry is placed into Gryffindor alongside Ron and Hermione, while Draco is placed into Slytherin, a house noted for dark wizards.
				As he studies magic, Harry learns more about his parents and Voldemort, and his natural talent for broomstick flying gets him recruited for the Gryffindor Quidditch team as the youngest Seeker in a century. While returning to the Gryffindor common room, the staircases change paths, leading Harry, Ron and Hermione to the third floor, which is forbidden to students. There they discover a giant three-headed dog named Fluffy. On Halloween, Ron insults Hermione after she shows off in Charms class; upset, she spends the entire afternoon crying in the girls' bathroom. That evening, a giant marauding troll enters it, but Harry and Ron save Hermione, and they make up and become close friends after Hermione takes the blame for the incident by claiming she went looking for the troll.
				The trio discover that Fluffy is guarding the philosopher's stone, a magical object that can turn metal into gold and produce an immortality elixir. Harry suspects that Potions teacher and head of Slytherin House, Severus Snape, wants the stone to return Voldemort to physical form. When Hagrid accidentally reveals that music puts Fluffy asleep, Harry, Ron and Hermione decide to find the stone before Snape. Fluffy is already asleep, but the trio face other barriers, including a deadly plant called Devil's Snare, a room filled with aggressive flying keys, and a giant chess game that knocks out Ron.
				After overcoming the barriers, Harry encounters Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher Quirinus Quirrell who wants the stone; Snape had figured it out and had been protecting Harry. Quirrell removes his turban to reveal a weakened Voldemort living on the back of his head. Dumbledore's protective enchantment places the stone in Harry's possession. Voldemort attempts to bargain the stone from Harry in exchange for resurrecting his parents, but Harry sees through his trick and refuses. Quirrell attempts to kill Harry. When Harry touches Quirrell's skin, it burns Quirrell, reducing him to ashes. Voldemort's soul rises from the pile and escapes, knocking out Harry as it passes through him.
				Harry recovers in the school infirmary. Dumbledore tells him the stone has been destroyed to prevent misuse, and that Ron and Hermione are safe. He also reveals how Harry defeated Quirrell: when Lily died to save Harry, a love-based protection against Voldemort was placed on him. At the end-of-school-year feast, Harry, Ron, and Hermione are rewarded extra house points for their heroism, tying Gryffindor for first place with Slytherin; Dumbledore then awards ten points to their housemate Neville Longbottom for having had the courage to stand up to the trio, granting Gryffindor the House Cup. Harry returns to the Dursleys for the summer, happy to finally have a real home at Hogwarts. 
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Heyday Films</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>1492 Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>125000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>Northumberland, County Durham,  North Yorkshire, London, Hertfordshire, Wiltshire</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Chris Colombus</name>
				<biography>	
							Chris Joseph Columbus(born September 10, 1958) is an American filmmaker. Born in Spangler, Pennsylvania, Columbus studied film at Tisch School of the Arts where he developed an interest in filmmaking. After writing screenplays for several teen comedies in the mid-1980s, he made his directorial debut with a teen adventure, Adventures in Babysitting (1987). Columbus gained recognition soon after with the highly successful Christmas comedy Home Alone (1990) and its sequel Home Alone 2: Lost in New York (1992).
							The comedy Mrs. Doubtfire (1993), starring Robin Williams, was another box office success for Columbus. He went on to direct several other films throughout the 1990s, which were mostly met with lukewarm reception. However, he found commercial success again for directing the film adaptations of J. K. Rowling's novels, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (2001) and its sequel, Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (2002), which are his highest-grossing films to date. In addition to directing, Columbus was a producer for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (2004), and the drama The Help (2011). He also directed the fantasy Percy Jackson and the Olympians: The Lightning Thief (2010) and the 3D action comedy Pixels (2015).
							Columbus is the co-founder of 1492 Pictures, a film production company that has produced some of his films since 1995. More recently, he co-founded another production firm with his daughter in 2014, called Maiden Voyage Pictures. In 2017, he launched ZAG Animation Studios, alongside Michael Barnathan, Haim Saban, and Jeremy Zag. Columbus is also known for his collaboration with composer John Williams, with whom he had worked on the films Home Alone and Harry Potter. 
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Steve Kloves</name>
				<biography>Stephen Keith Kloves(born March 18, 1960) is an American filmmaker. He wrote and directed the 1989 film The Fabulous Baker Boys and is mainly known for his adaptations of novels, especially for all but one of the Harry Potter films (the exception being Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix) and for Wonder Boys, for which he was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay. </biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Joanne Kathleen Rowling</name>
				<biography>	
							Joanne Rowling CH OBE FRSL (born 31 July 1965), best known by her pen name J. K. Rowling, is a British author and philanthropist. She wrote Harry Potter, a seven-volume fantasy series published from 1997 to 2007. The series has sold over 600 million copies, been translated into 84 languages, and spawned a global media franchise including films and video games. The Casual Vacancy (2012) was her first novel for adults. She writes Cormoran Strike, an ongoing crime fiction series, under the alias Robert Galbraith.
							Born in Yate, Gloucestershire, Rowling was working as a researcher and bilingual secretary for Amnesty International in 1990 when she conceived the idea for the Harry Potter series while on a delayed train from Manchester to London. The seven-year period that followed saw the death of her mother, the birth of her first child, divorce from her first husband, and relative poverty until the first novel in the series, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, was published in 1997. Six sequels followed, and by 2008, Forbes had named her the world's highest-paid author.
							Rowling concluded the Harry Potter series with Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows (2007). The novels follow a boy called Harry Potter as he attends Hogwarts (a school for wizards), and battles Lord Voldemort. Death and the divide between good and evil are the central themes of the series. Its influences include Bildungsroman (the coming-of-age genre), school stories, fairy tales, and Christian allegory. The series revived fantasy as a genre in the children's market, spawned a host of imitators, and inspired an active fandom. Critical reception has been more mixed. Many reviewers see Rowling's writing as conventional; some regard her portrayal of gender and social division as regressive. There were also religious debates over the Harry Potter series.
							Rowling has won many accolades for her work. She has received an OBE and made a Companion of Honour for services to literature and philanthropy. Harry Potter brought her wealth and recognition, which she has used to advance philanthropic endeavours and political causes. She co-founded the charity Lumos and established the Volant Charitable Trust, named after her mother. Rowling's charitable giving centres on medical causes and supporting at-risk women and children. In politics, she has donated to Britain's Labour Party and opposed Scottish independence and Brexit. She has publicly expressed her opinions on transgender people and related civil rights since 2017. These have been criticised as transphobic by LGBT rights organisations and some feminists, but have received support from other feminists and individuals.  
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Heyman</name>
				<biography>David Jonathan Heyman (born 26 July 1961) is a British film producer and the founder of Heyday Films. Heyman is best known as the primary producer of all eight installments of the Harry Potter film series, which are based on a series of popular fantasy novels of the same name by author J. K. Rowling. He then produced all three installments of its spin-off prequel series, Fantastic Beasts. His work makes him the second-most commercially successful producer of all time.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>John Williams</name>
				<biography>	
							John Towner Williams (born February 8, 1932) is an American composer, conductor, and pianist. In a career that has spanned seven decades, he has composed some of the most popular, recognizable and critically acclaimed film scores in cinema history. Williams has won 25 Grammy Awards, five Academy Awards, seven British Academy Film Awards, and four Golden Globe Awards. With 53 Academy Award nominations, he is the second most-nominated individual, after only Walt Disney. His compositions are considered the epitome of film music, and he is considered among the greatest composers in the history of cinema.Williams has composed many of his film scoring works for frequent collaborators Steven Spielberg and George Lucas, and other directors such as Chris Columbus, Oliver Stone, Richard Donner, Irvin Kershner, Sydney Pollack, Alfred Hitchcock, Mark Rydell, Mark Robson, Jean-Jacques Annaud, Robert Altman, and J. J. Abrams. He has a very distinct and recognizable sound that mixes romanticism, impressionism and atonal music with complex orchestration.
							Williams has been associated with director Steven Spielberg since 1974, composing music for all but five of his feature films, and George Lucas, with whom he has worked on both of his main franchises, Star Wars and Indiana Jones. His early work as a film composer includes The Killers (1964), How to Steal a Million (1966), Valley of the Dolls (1967), and Goodbye Mr. Chips (1969). He has received five Academy Awards for Best Original Score for his work on Fiddler on the Roof (1971), Jaws (1975), Star Wars (1977), E.T.: The Extra Terrestrial (1982), and Schindler's List (1993). Williams has composed for many popular films including the Star Wars saga, Superman, the first two Home Alone films, the Indiana Jones films, the first two Jurassic Park films, and the first three Harry Potter films. Other memorable film scores from his collaboration with Spielberg include Close Encounters of the Third Kind (1977), Hook (1991), Saving Private Ryan (1998), Catch Me If You Can (2002), War of the Worlds (2005), War Horse (2011), Lincoln (2012), and The Fabelmans (2022).
							Williams has also composed numerous classical concertos and other works for orchestral ensembles and solo instruments. He served as the Boston Pops' principal conductor from 1980 to 1993 and is its laureate conductor.Other works by Williams include theme music for the 1984 Summer Olympic Games, NBC Sunday Night Football, "The Mission" theme used by NBC News and Seven News in Australia, the television series Lost in Space and Land of the Giants, and the incidental music for the first season of Gilligan's Island. Williams announced but then rescinded his intention to retire from film score composing after the release of Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny in 2023.
							In 2005, the American Film Institute selected Williams's score to 1977's Star Wars as the greatest film score of all time. The Library of Congress entered the Star Wars soundtrack into the National Recording Registry for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant". Williams was inducted into the Hollywood Bowl's Hall of Fame in 2000, and he received a Kennedy Center Honor in 2004. His AFI Life Achievement Award in 2016 was the first to be awarded outside of the acting and directing fields. He has composed the score for nine of the top 25 highest-grossing films at the U.S. box office (adjusted for inflation). His work has influenced other composers of film, popular, and contemporary classical music.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Daniel Radcliffe</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Harry Potter</character>
					<character_description>An 11-year-old orphan living with his unwelcoming aunt, uncle, and cousin, who learns of his own fame as a wizard known to have survived his parents' murder at the hands of the dark wizard Lord Voldemort as an infant when he is accepted to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. Columbus had wanted Radcliffe for the role since he saw him in the BBC's production of David Copperfield, before the open casting sessions had taken place, but had been told by casting director Susan Figgis that Radcliffe's protective parents would not allow their son to take the part. Columbus explained that his persistence in giving Radcliffe the role was responsible for Figgis' resignation. Radcliffe was asked to audition in 2000, when Heyman and Kloves met him and his parents at a production of Stones in His Pockets in London. Heyman and Columbus successfully managed to convince Radcliffe's parents that their son would be protected from media intrusion, and they agreed to let him play Harry. Rowling approved of Radcliffe's casting, stating that "having seen his screen test I don't think Chris Columbus could have found a better Harry." Radcliffe was reportedly paid £1 million for the film, although he felt the fee was "not that important" to him. The Saunders triplets appear as Harry as a baby.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Emma Watson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Hermione Granger</character>
					<character_description>Harry's other best friend and the trio's brains. Watson's Oxford theatre teacher passed her name on to the casting agents and she had to do over five interviews before she got the part. Watson took her audition seriously, but "never really thought she had any chance of getting the role." The producers were impressed by Watson's self-confidence and she outperformed the thousands of other girls who had applied.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Rupert Grint</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Ron Wealsey</character>
					<character_description>Harry's best friend at Hogwarts and a younger member of the Weasley wizarding family. A fan of the series, Grint decided he would be perfect for the part "because he has ginger hair". Having seen a Newsround report about the open casting he sent in a video of himself rapping about how he wished to receive the part. His attempt was successful as the casting team asked for a meeting with him.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian Hart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Professor Quirrell</character>
					<character_description>The stuttering Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian Hart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Lord Voldemort</character>
					<character_description>Voldemort, an anagrammatic sobriquet for Tom Marvolo Riddle, is the archenemy of Harry Potter, who according to a prophecy has "the power to vanquish the Dark Lord". He attempts to murder the boy, but instead kills his parents, Lily and James Potter, and leaves Harry with a scar on his forehead in the shape of a lightning bolt. Nearly every witch or wizard dares not utter his name and refers to him instead with such monikers as "You-Know-Who", "He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named", or "The Dark Lord". Voldemort's obsession with blood purity signifies his aim to rid the wizarding world of Muggle (non-magical) heritage and to conquer both worlds, Muggle and wizarding, to achieve pure-blood dominance. Through his mother's family, he is the last descendant of the wizard Salazar Slytherin, one of the four founders of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. He is the leader of the Death Eaters, a group of evil wizards and witches dedicated to ridding the Wizarding World of Muggles and establishing Voldemort as its supreme ruler. </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Alan Rickman</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Severus Snape</character>
					<character_description>The Potions Master and head of Slytherin House.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Richard Harris</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Albus Dumbledore</character>
					<character_description>Hogwarts' Headmaster and one of the most famous and powerful wizards of all time. Harris initially rejected the role, only to reverse his decision after his granddaughter stated she would never speak to him again if he did not take it.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Tom Felton</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Draco Malfoy</character>
					<character_description>A student in Slytherin and Harry's rival.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard Francis-Bruce</name>
				<biography>Richard Leslie Francis-Bruce AM (born 10 December 1948) is an Australian film editor who has received several nominations for the Academy Award for Best Film Editing. </biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>John A. Midgley</name>
				<biography>John Midgley is an English sound engineer. He won an Oscar in the category Best Sound Mixing for Hugo and has been nominated for another two. He has worked on more than 100 films since 1977.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company>
					<name>Warner Bros. Pictures</name>
				</company>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company>
					<name>Peacock</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Prime Video</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Max</name>
				</company>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.8</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.6</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>81</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>1024254401</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-2" title="Green Mile" genre="Drama" release_date="1999-12-10" duration="189" rating="PG">
		<plot>
				At a Louisiana assisted-living home in 1999, retiree Paul Edgecomb begins to cry while watching the film Top Hat. His companion Elaine becomes concerned, and Paul explains to her that the film reminded him of events that he witnessed when he was an officer at Cold Mountain Penitentiary's death row, nicknamed "The Green Mile".
				In 1935, Paul supervised Corrections Officers Brutus "Brutal" Howell, Dean Stanton, Harry Terwilliger, and Percy Wetmore, reporting to Warden Hal Moores. Percy, the nephew of the state governor's wife, demonstrates a severe sadistic streak but flaunts his family connections to avoid being held accountable. He is particularly abusive towards prisoner Eduard "Del" Delacroix, breaking his fingers and killing his pet mouse, Mr. Jingles.
				Paul is introduced to John Coffey, a physically imposing but mild-mannered black man sentenced to death after being convicted of raping and murdering two young white girls. He joins Del and another condemned convict: Arlen Bitterbuck, the first to be executed. The officers are forced to deal with psychotic new inmate William "Wild Bill" Wharton, who frequently causes trouble by assaulting the officers and racially abusing John, forcing them to restrain him in the block's padded cell on more than one occasion.
				After John heals Paul's severe bladder infection by touching him, and later resurrects Mr. Jingles, Paul gradually realizes that John possesses a supernatural ability to heal others. Paul doubts whether someone with the power to perform divine miracles is truly guilty of the crime.
				In exchange for resigning from the penitentiary and accepting a job at an insane asylum, Percy is allowed to oversee Del's execution. At the execution, Percy deliberately avoids soaking the sponge used to conduct electricity to Del's head, leading to Del suffering a gruesome and agonizing death by burning, with John forced to feel Del's pain as well. Paul and the other officers punish Percy by forcing him to spend a night in the padded cell. While Percy is locked away, they drug Wharton and secretly smuggle John out of the prison so that he can use his powers to heal Warden Moores' wife Melinda of a brain tumor, saving her life. After Percy is released from the padded room, the others threaten to report him for his various acts of misconduct if his behavior continues.
				John uses his powers to "release" Melinda's affliction into Percy's brain, causing Percy to shoot Wharton dead. Soon after, John reveals in a vision to Paul that Wharton was the true culprit of the crimes for which he was wrongfully condemned, releasing his supernatural energy into Paul in the process. Having gone into a catatonic state, Percy is committed to the same insane asylum where he had planned to work after resigning from the prison.
				After realizing that John is innocent, Paul becomes distraught at the thought of executing him and offers to let him go free. John tells Paul that the execution would be an act of mercy, as he views the world as a cruel place and is in constant pain from the suffering that people inflict upon each other. Mentioning that he has never seen a movie before, John watches Top Hat with the other officers as his last request. As John is taken to be executed, he is mercilessly scorned by the parents of the two girls who still believe him to be guilty. He asks not to have a hood placed over his head as he is afraid of the dark. Paul, Brutal, and the officers watch in great sadness, visibly holding back tears as John is executed.
				Back in present day, Paul tells Elaine that John's execution was the last that he and Brutal witnessed, as they both subsequently resigned from the prison and took jobs in the juvenile system. Paul reveals to Elaine that Mr. Jingles is still alive, having been blessed with a supernaturally long life thanks to John's healing touch. He also reveals that he is now 108 years old; he was 44 when John was executed. While Elaine sees Paul's long life as another of John's miracles, Paul speculates that he may have been condemned to linger on Earth and outlive all of his loved ones as a divine punishment for John's execution. Paul later attends Elaine's funeral and muses on how much longer he has left to live, saying, "We each owe a death. There are no exceptions. But, oh, God... sometimes, the Green Mile seems so long."
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company>
					<name>Castle Rock Entertainment </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Darkwoods Productions</name>
				</company>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>60000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>United States</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>	
					Frank Árpád Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959) is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007).
					Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).	
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>Frank Árpád Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959) is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007). Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>Frank Árpád Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959)[2] is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007).Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Valdes</name>
				<biography>David Valdes (born August 12, 1950, in Los Angeles) is an American film producer known for working in the western genre and collaborating with Clint Eastwood. His first production experience was as a guest on a film called Diary of a Mad Housewife, which was shot in his hometown in 1969.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Thomas Newman</name>
				<biography>	
					Thomas Montgomery Newman (born October 20, 1955) is an American composer and conductor best known for his many film scores. In a career that has spanned over four decades, he has scored numerous films including The Player (1992), The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Horse Whisperer (1998), American Beauty and The Green Mile (both 1999), In the Bedroom (2001), Road to Perdition and White Oleander (both 2002), Finding Nemo (2003), Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events (2004), Cinderella Man (2005), WALL-E (2008), the James Bond films Skyfall (2012) and Spectre (2015), Finding Dory (2016), 1917 (2019), and Elemental (2023). He also composed the music for the 2003 HBO miniseries Angels in America. Throughout his career, he has collaborated extensively with directors such as Sam Mendes, Andrew Stanton, Frank Darabont, Steven Soderbergh, Jon Avnet, John Madden and John Lee Hancock.
					Newman has been nominated for fifteen Academy Awards, tying him with fellow composer Alex North for the most nominations without a win. He has also been nominated for four Golden Globes, and has won two BAFTAs, six Grammys and an Emmy Award. Newman was honored with the Richard Kirk award at the 2000 BMI Film and TV Awards. The award is given annually to a composer who has made significant contributions to film and television music.[1] His achievements have contributed to the Newmans being the most nominated Academy Award extended family, with a collective 92 nominations in various music categories.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Tom Hanks</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Paul Edgecomb</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>David Morse</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Brutus Howell</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Michael Clarke Duncan</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>John Coffey</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Sam Rockwell</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Wild Bill</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Patricia Clarkson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Melinda Moores</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Bonnie Hunt</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Jan Engecomb</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard Francis-Bruce</name>
				<biography>Richard Leslie Francis-Bruce AM (born 10 December 1948) is an Australian film editor who has received several nominations for the Academy Award for Best Film Editing. </biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Robert J. Litt</name>
				<biography> </biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.0</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>8.6</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>79</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>286800000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-3" title="Titanic" genre="Drama" release_date="1997-11-01" duration="195" rating="PG">
		<plot>
			In 1996, aboard the research vessel Akademik Mstislav Keldysh, Brock Lovett and his team search the wreck of RMS Titanic. They recover a safe they hope contains a necklace with a large diamond known as the Heart of the Ocean. Instead, they find only a drawing of a young nude woman wearing the necklace. The sketch is dated April 14, 1912, the same day the Titanic struck the iceberg that caused it to sink. After viewing a television news story about the discovery, centenarian Rose Dawson Calvert contacts Lovett, identifying herself as the woman in the drawing. Hoping she can help locate the necklace, Lovett brings Rose aboard Keldysh, where she recounts her experiences as a Titanic passenger.
			In 1912 Southampton, 17-year-old Rose DeWitt Bukater, her wealthy fiancé Caledon "Cal" Hockley and Rose's widowed mother Ruth board the Titanic. Ruth emphasizes that Rose's marrying Cal will resolve the family's financial problems and maintain their upper-class status. Meanwhile, Jack Dawson, a poor young artist, wins a third-class Titanic ticket in a poker game. After setting sail, Rose, distraught over her loveless engagement, climbs over the stern railing, intending to commit suicide. Jack coaxes her back onto the deck and they develop a friendship. Jack soon admits that he has feelings for Rose. When Cal and Ruth object, Rose rejects Jack's attentions, but returns to him after realizing she has fallen in love.
			Rose brings Jack to her state room and requests he draw her nude, wearing only the Heart of the Ocean. They later evade Cal's servant, Lovejoy, and have sex in a Renault Towncar inside the cargo hold. On the forward deck, they witness the ship's collision with an iceberg and overhear its officers discussing its seriousness. Cal discovers Jack's sketch and an insulting note from Rose in his safe, along with the necklace. When Jack and Rose return to warn the others about the collision, Cal has Lovejoy slip the necklace into Jack's pocket to frame him for theft. Jack is confined in the master-at-arms' office. Cal puts the necklace into his own overcoat pocket.
			With the ship sinking, the crew prioritize women and children for evacuation. Rose finds and frees Jack, and they make it back to the deck, where Cal and Jack urge Rose to board a lifeboat. Intending to save himself, Cal lies that he will get Jack safely off the ship and wraps his overcoat around Rose. As her lifeboat is lowered, Rose, unable to abandon Jack, jumps back onto the ship. Cal grabs Lovejoy's pistol and chases Jack and Rose, but they escape. Cal realizes the necklace is still in the coat he gave Rose. He poses as a lost child's father to board a lifeboat.
			Jack and Rose return to the deck. The ship's stern is rising as the flooded bow sinks; the two desperately cling to the stern rail. The upended ship breaks in half and the bow section sinks. The stern slams back onto the ocean, upends again and sinks. In the freezing water, Jack helps Rose onto a wood transom panel among the debris, buoyant enough only for one person, and makes her promise to survive. Jack dies of cold shock, but Rose is among six people saved by the one returning lifeboat. RMS Carpathia rescues the survivors. Rose avoids Cal and her mother by hiding among the steerage passengers and giving her name as Rose Dawson. Still wearing Cal's overcoat, she discovers the necklace tucked inside the pocket.
			In the present, Rose says she heard that Cal committed suicide after losing his fortune in the Wall Street Crash of 1929. Lovett abandons his search after hearing Rose's story. Alone on the stern of Keldysh, Rose takes the Heart of the Ocean, which has been in her possession all along, and drops it into the sea over the wreck site. While she is seemingly asleep in her bed, her photos on the dresser depict a life of freedom and adventure inspired by Jack. A young Rose reunites with Jack at the Titanic's Grand Staircase, applauded by those who died that night.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company>
					<name>Paramount Pictures</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>20th Century Studios</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>Lightstorm Entertainment</name>
				</company>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>200000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>United States</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>James Cameron</name>
				<biography>	
					James Francis Cameron CC (born August 16, 1954) is a Canadian filmmaker. A major figure in the post-New Hollywood era, Cameron is considered one of the industry's most innovative filmmakers, regularly making use of novel technologies. He first gained recognition for writing and directing The Terminator (1984) and found further success with Aliens (1986), The Abyss (1989), Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991), and the action comedy True Lies (1994). He wrote and directed Titanic (1997), Avatar (2009) and its sequels, with Titanic earning him Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Film Editing. A recipient of various other industry accolades, two of his films have been selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library of Congress.
					Cameron co-founded the production companies Lightstorm Entertainment, Digital Domain, and Earthship Productions. In addition to filmmaking, he is a National Geographic sea tourist and has produced many documentaries on the subject, including Ghosts of the Abyss (2003) and Aliens of the Deep (2005). Cameron has also contributed to underwater filming and remote vehicle technologies and helped create the digital 3D Fusion Camera System. In 2012, Cameron became the first person to do a solo descent to the bottom of the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth's ocean, in the Deepsea Challenger submersible.
					Cameron's films have grossed over $8 billion worldwide, making him the second-highest-grossing film director of all time. Three of Cameron's films are amongst the top four highest-grossing films of all time; Avatar (2009), Avatar: The Way of Water (2022) and Titanic (1997) are the highest, third-highest and fourth-highest-grossing films of all time, respectively.[1] Cameron directed the first film to gross over $1 billion, the first two films to gross over $2 billion, and is the only director to have had three films gross over $2 billion.[2][3] In 2010, Time named Cameron one of the 100 most influential people in the world. Cameron is also an environmentalist and runs several sustainability businesses.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>James Cameron</name>
				<biography>	
					James Francis Cameron CC (born August 16, 1954) is a Canadian filmmaker. A major figure in the post-New Hollywood era, Cameron is considered one of the industry's most innovative filmmakers, regularly making use of novel technologies. He first gained recognition for writing and directing The Terminator (1984) and found further success with Aliens (1986), The Abyss (1989), Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991), and the action comedy True Lies (1994). He wrote and directed Titanic (1997), Avatar (2009) and its sequels, with Titanic earning him Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Film Editing. A recipient of various other industry accolades, two of his films have been selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library of Congress.
					Cameron co-founded the production companies Lightstorm Entertainment, Digital Domain, and Earthship Productions. In addition to filmmaking, he is a National Geographic sea tourist and has produced many documentaries on the subject, including Ghosts of the Abyss (2003) and Aliens of the Deep (2005). Cameron has also contributed to underwater filming and remote vehicle technologies and helped create the digital 3D Fusion Camera System. In 2012, Cameron became the first person to do a solo descent to the bottom of the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth's ocean, in the Deepsea Challenger submersible.
					Cameron's films have grossed over $8 billion worldwide, making him the second-highest-grossing film director of all time. Three of Cameron's films are amongst the top four highest-grossing films of all time; Avatar (2009), Avatar: The Way of Water (2022) and Titanic (1997) are the highest, third-highest and fourth-highest-grossing films of all time, respectively.[1] Cameron directed the first film to gross over $1 billion, the first two films to gross over $2 billion, and is the only director to have had three films gross over $2 billion.[2][3] In 2010, Time named Cameron one of the 100 most influential people in the world. Cameron is also an environmentalist and runs several sustainability businesses.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>James Cameron</name>
				<biography>	
					James Francis Cameron CC (born August 16, 1954) is a Canadian filmmaker. A major figure in the post-New Hollywood era, Cameron is considered one of the industry's most innovative filmmakers, regularly making use of novel technologies. He first gained recognition for writing and directing The Terminator (1984) and found further success with Aliens (1986), The Abyss (1989), Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991), and the action comedy True Lies (1994). He wrote and directed Titanic (1997), Avatar (2009) and its sequels, with Titanic earning him Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Film Editing. A recipient of various other industry accolades, two of his films have been selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library of Congress.
					Cameron co-founded the production companies Lightstorm Entertainment, Digital Domain, and Earthship Productions. In addition to filmmaking, he is a National Geographic sea tourist and has produced many documentaries on the subject, including Ghosts of the Abyss (2003) and Aliens of the Deep (2005). Cameron has also contributed to underwater filming and remote vehicle technologies and helped create the digital 3D Fusion Camera System. In 2012, Cameron became the first person to do a solo descent to the bottom of the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth's ocean, in the Deepsea Challenger submersible.
					Cameron's films have grossed over $8 billion worldwide, making him the second-highest-grossing film director of all time. Three of Cameron's films are amongst the top four highest-grossing films of all time; Avatar (2009), Avatar: The Way of Water (2022) and Titanic (1997) are the highest, third-highest and fourth-highest-grossing films of all time, respectively.[1] Cameron directed the first film to gross over $1 billion, the first two films to gross over $2 billion, and is the only director to have had three films gross over $2 billion.[2][3] In 2010, Time named Cameron one of the 100 most influential people in the world. Cameron is also an environmentalist and runs several sustainability businesses.
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Jon Landau</name>
				<biography>Jon Landau (/ˈlændaʊ/) (born July 23, 1960)[1] is an American film producer, known for producing Titanic (1997), a film which won him an Oscar and earned $2.19 billion in gross revenues, as well as Avatar (2009) and Avatar: The Way of Water (2022), which earned $2.9 billion and $2.2 billion respectively. As of 2023, these are three of the four highest-grossing films of all time.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>James Horner</name>
				<biography>	
					James Roy Horner (August 14, 1953 – June 22, 2015) was an American composer of film scores. He worked on over 160 film and television productions between 1978 and 2015, and was the winner of two Academy Awards, among many other accolades. He was known for the integration of choral and electronic elements alongside traditional orchestrations, and for his use of motifs associated with Celtic music.[1][2]
					Horner won two Academy Awards for James Cameron's Titanic (1997), for which he composed the best-selling orchestral film soundtrack of all time.[3][4] He also wrote the score for the highest-grossing film of all time, Cameron's Avatar.[5] Horner's other Oscar-nominated scores were for Aliens (1986), An American Tail (1986), Field of Dreams (1989), Apollo 13 (1995), Braveheart (1995), A Beautiful Mind (2001), and House of Sand and Fog (2003). Horner's other notable scores include Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan (1982),[6] Willow (1988), The Land Before Time (1988), Glory (1989), The Rocketeer (1991), Legends of the Fall (1994), Jumanji (1995), The Mask of Zorro (1998), How the Grinch Stole Christmas (2000), Troy (2004), The New World (2005), Apocalypto (2006), and The Karate Kid (2010).
					Horner collaborated on multiple projects with directors including Don Bluth, James Cameron, Jean-Jacques Annaud, Joe Johnston, Walter Hill, Mel Gibson, Vadim Perelman, Ron Howard, Edward Zwick, Nicholas Meyer, Wolfgang Petersen, Martin Campbell, Phil Nibbelink and Simon Wells; producers including George Lucas, David Kirschner, Lawrence Gordon, Jon Landau, Brian Grazer and Steven Spielberg; and songwriters including Will Jennings, Barry Mann and Cynthia Weil. He won two Academy Awards; Best Original Score for Titanic and Best Original Song for "My Heart Will Go On", six Grammy Awards, two Golden Globes, and was nominated for three BAFTA Awards.
					Horner, who was an avid pilot, was killed in a single-fatality crash while flying his Short Tucano turboprop aircraft. He was 61 years old.[7] The scores for his final three films, Southpaw (2015), The 33 (2015) and The Magnificent Seven (2016), were all completed and released posthumously.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Leonardo DiCaprio</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Jack Dawson</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Kate Winslet</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Rose DeWitt BuKater</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Billy Zane</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Cadelon Hockley</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Kathy Bates</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Molly Brown</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Gloria Stuart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Rose DeWitt BuKater</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Conrad Buff</name>
				<biography>Conrad Buff IV (born July 8, 1948) is an American film editor with more than 25 film credits since 1985. Buff is known for winning an Academy Award for Best Film Editing and an ACE Eddie Award for Titanic (1997); the awards were shared with his co-editors James Cameron and Richard A. Harris. He won the 2000 Satellite Award for Best Editing for Thirteen Days.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard A. Harris</name>
				<biography>Richard A. Harris (born February 6, 1934) is an American film editor with a career spanning nearly forty years. He graduated from the School of Cinematic Arts of the University of Southern California in 1956. He is most associated with the films of Michael Ritchie (Downhill Racer, The Candidate, An Almost Perfect Affair) and James Cameron (Terminator 2: Judgment Day, True Lies).</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Christopher Boyes</name>
				<biography>Christopher Boyes is an American sound engineer. He has won four Academy Awards and has been nominated for another eleven. He has worked on more than 100 films since 1991.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.0</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.9</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>88</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>2257000000000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-4" title="The Lord of the Rings" genre="Fantastic" release_date="1997-11-01" duration="195" rating="PG">
		<plot>
			In the Second Age of Middle-earth, the lords of Elves, Dwarves, and Men are given Rings of Power. Unbeknownst to them, the Dark Lord Sauron forges the One Ring in 			Mount Doom, instilling into it a great part of his power, to dominate the other Rings and conquer Middle-earth. A final alliance of Men and Elves battles Sauron's 			forces in Mordor. Isildur of Gondor severs Sauron's finger and the Ring with it, thereby vanquishing Sauron and returning him to spirit form. With Sauron's first 			defeat, the Third Age of Middle-earth begins. The Ring's influence corrupts Isildur, who takes it for himself and is later killed by Orcs. The Ring is lost in a 			river for 2,500 years until it is found by Gollum, who owns it for over four and a half centuries. The ring abandons Gollum and it is subsequently found by a hobbit 			named Bilbo Baggins, who is unaware of its history.
			Sixty years later, Bilbo celebrates his 111th birthday in the Shire, reuniting with his old friend, the wizard Gandalf the Grey. Bilbo departs the Shire for one 			last adventure, and he leaves his inheritance, including the Ring, to his nephew Frodo. Gandalf investigates the Ring, discovers its true nature, and learns that 			Gollum was captured and brutally tortured by Sauron's Orcs, revealing two words during his interrogation: "Shire" and "Baggins." Gandalf returns and warns Frodo to 			leave the Shire. As Frodo departs with his friend, gardener Samwise Gamgee, Gandalf rides to Isengard to meet with the wizard Saruman, but discovers his betrayal 			and alliance with Sauron, who has dispatched his nine undead Nazgûl servants to find Frodo.
			Frodo and Sam are joined by fellow hobbits Merry and Pippin, and they evade the Nazgûl before arriving in Bree, where they are meant to meet Gandalf at the Inn of 			The Prancing Pony. However, Gandalf never arrives, having been taken prisoner by Saruman. The hobbits are then aided by a Ranger named Strider, who promises to 			escort them to Rivendell; however, they are ambushed by the Nazgûl on Weathertop, and their leader, the Witch-King, stabs Frodo with a Morgul blade. Arwen, an Elf 			and Strider's beloved, locates Strider and rescues Frodo, summoning flood-waters that sweep the Nazgûl away. She takes him to Rivendell, where he is healed by the 			Elves. Frodo meets with Gandalf, who escaped Isengard on a Great Eagle. That night, Strider reunites with Arwen, and they affirm their love for each other.
			Learning of Saruman's betrayal from Gandalf and now realizing that they are facing threats from both Sauron and Saruman, Arwen's father, Lord Elrond, decides 				against keeping the Ring in Rivendell. He holds a council of Elves, Men, and Dwarves, also attended by Frodo and Gandalf, that decides the Ring must be destroyed in 			the fires of Mount Doom. Frodo volunteers to take the Ring, accompanied by Gandalf, Sam, Merry, Pippin, Elf Legolas, Dwarf Gimli, Boromir of Gondor, and Strider—who 			is actually Aragorn, Isildur's heir and the rightful King of Gondor. Bilbo, now living in Rivendell, gives Frodo his sword Sting, and a chainmail shirt made of 			mithril.
			The Fellowship of the Ring makes for the Gap of Rohan, but discover it is being watched by Saruman's spies. They instead set off over the mountain pass of 				Caradhras, but Saruman summons a storm that forces them to travel through the Mines of Moria, where a tentacled water beast blocks off the entrance with the 				Fellowship inside, giving them no choice but to journey to the exit on the other end. After finding the Dwarves of Moria dead, the Fellowship is attacked by Orcs 			and a cave troll. They hold them off but are confronted by Durin's Bane: a Balrog residing within the mines. While the others escape, Gandalf fends off the Balrog 			and casts it into a vast chasm, but the Balrog drags Gandalf down into the darkness with him. The devastated Fellowship reaches Lothlórien, ruled by the Elf-queen 			Galadriel, who privately informs Frodo that only he can complete the quest and that one of the Fellowship will try to take the Ring. She also shows him a vision of 			the future in which Sauron succeeds in enslaving Middle-earth, including the Shire. Meanwhile, Saruman creates an army of Uruk-hai in Isengard to find and kill the 			Fellowship.
			The Fellowship travels by river to Parth Galen. Frodo wanders off and is confronted by Boromir, who, as Lady Galadriel had warned, tries to take the Ring. Uruk-hai 			scouts then ambush the Fellowship, attempting to abduct the Hobbits. Boromir breaks free of the Ring's magic and protects Merry and Pippin, but the Uruk-Hai leader, 			Lurtz, mortally wounds Boromir as they abduct the Hobbits. Aragorn arrives and kills Lurtz before comforting Boromir as he dies, promising to help the people of 			Gondor in the coming conflict. Fearing the Ring will corrupt his friends, Frodo decides to travel to Mordor alone, but allows Sam to come along, recalling his 				promise to Gandalf to look after him. As Aragorn, Legolas, and Gimli set out to rescue Merry and Pippin, Frodo and Sam make their way down the mountain pass of Emyn 			Muil, journeying on to Mordor.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company>
					<name>New Line Cinema</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>WingNut Films</name>
				</company>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>93000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>United States, New Zealand </cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Peter Jackson</name>
				<biography>	
					Sir Peter Robert Jackson ONZ KNZM (born 31 October 1961) is a New Zealand film director, screenwriter and producer. He is best known as the 						director, writer and producer of the Lord of the Rings trilogy (2001–2003) and the Hobbit trilogy (2012–2014), both of which are adapted from the 					novels of the same name by J. R. R. Tolkien. Other notable films include the critically lauded drama Heavenly Creatures (1994), the horror comedy 					The Frighteners (1996), the epic monster remake film King Kong (2005), the World War I documentary film They Shall Not Grow Old (2018) and the 						documentary The Beatles: Get Back (2021). He is the fourth-highest-grossing film director of all-time, his films having made over $6.5 billion 						worldwide.
					Jackson began his career with the "splatstick" horror comedy Bad Taste (1987) and the black comedy Meet the Feebles (1989) before filming the zombie 					comedy Braindead (1992). He shared a nomination for Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay with his partner Fran Walsh[2] for Heavenly 						Creatures, which brought him to mainstream prominence in the film industry. Jackson has been awarded three Academy Awards for The Lord of the Rings: 					The Return of the King (2003), including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Adapted Screenplay, His other awards include three BAFTAs, a Golden 					Globe, two Primetime Emmy Awards and four Saturn Awards among others.
					His production company is WingNut Films, and his most regular collaborators are co-writers and producers Walsh and Philippa Boyens. Jackson was made 					a Companion of the New Zealand Order of Merit in 2002. He was later knighted (as a Knight Companion of the order) by Sir Anand Satyanand, the 						Governor-General of New Zealand, at a ceremony in Wellington in April 2010. In December 2014, Jackson was awarded a star on the Hollywood Walk of 					Fame.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Fran Walsh</name>
				<biography>	
					Dame Frances Rosemary Walsh DNZM (born 10 January 1959)[1] is a New Zealand screenwriter and film producer.
					The partner of filmmaker Peter Jackson, Walsh has contributed to all of their films since 1989: as co-writer since Meet the Feebles, and as producer 					since The Lord of the Rings Trilogy. She has won three Academy Awards for the final film of the trilogy, The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the 					King.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Philippa Boyens</name>
				<biography>	
					Born in 1962, Boyens is the daughter of John Fraser Boyens and Jane Moana Menhennet. She was educated at Massey High School, and was later a part-time student at the University of Auckland, graduating with a BA in English and history in 1994. After that Boyens joined a theatre company and her wages were paid by the government in a PEP scheme. Boyens received a Distinguished Alumni Award from the University and Auckland in 2006. Boyens co-wrote the screenplay for Peter Jackson's films The Lord of the Rings series, King Kong, The Lovely Bones, and the three-part film The Hobbit, all with Jackson and Fran Walsh. Boyens, Jackson, and Walsh won the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay for The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King at the 76th Academy Awards in 2004. She was co-producer on every one of Jackson's films since King Kong, and on District 9. Prior to screen-writing, Boyens worked in theater as a playwright, teacher, producer, and editor. Boyens was director of the New Zealand Writers Guild for a time.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Barrie M. Osborne</name>
				<biography>	
					The son of Hertha Schwarz and William Osborne, Barrie was born in New York City and grew up in New Rochelle, New York where he graduated New Rochelle High School. He is an alumnus of Carleton College in Northfield, Minnesota and currently lives in Wellington, New Zealand. He was appointed an Officer of the New Zealand Order of Merit (ONZM), for services to the film industry, in the 2017 New Year Honours. Osborne's most notable work is The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King for which he, Peter Jackson, and Fran Walsh received the Academy Award for Best Picture. He also produced the 2013 The Great Gatsby remake, starring Leonardo DiCaprio. In 2014, Osborne, Alan B. Curtiss, and Mexican entrepreneur Max Appedole, released Gloria, a biopic of controversial Mexican pop star Gloria Trevi, directed by Christian Keller. Osborne is also preparing a possible movie trilogy about the Viking king Harald Hardrada.
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Peter Jackson</name>
				<biography>Sir Peter Robert Jackson ONZ KNZM (born 31 October 1961) is a New Zealand film director, screenwriter and producer. He is best known as the director, writer and producer of the Lord of the Rings trilogy (2001–2003) and the Hobbit trilogy (2012–2014), both of which are adapted from the novels of the same name by J. R. R. Tolkien. Other notable films include the critically lauded drama Heavenly Creatures (1994), the horror comedy The Frighteners (1996), the epic monster remake film King Kong (2005), the World War I documentary film They Shall Not Grow Old (2018) and the documentary The Beatles: Get Back (2021). He is the fourth-highest-grossing film director of all-time, his films having made over $6.5 billion worldwide Jackson began his career with the "splatstick" horror comedy Bad Taste (1987) and the black comedy Meet the Feebles (1989) before filming the zombie comedy Braindead (1992). He shared a nomination for Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay with his partner Fran Walsh[2] for Heavenly 	Creatures, which brought him to mainstream prominence in the film industry. Jackson has been awarded three Academy Awards for The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King (2003), including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Adapted Screenplay, His other awards include three BAFTAs, a Golden Globe, two Primetime Emmy Awards and four Saturn Awards among others.
					His production company is WingNut Films, and his most regular collaborators are co-writers and producers Walsh and Philippa Boyens. Jackson was made a Companion of the New Zealand Order of Merit in 2002. He was later knighted (as a Knight Companion of the order) by Sir Anand Satyanand, the Governor-General of New Zealand, at a ceremony in Wellington in April 2010. In December 2014, Jackson was awarded a star on the Hollywood Walk of 					Fame.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Howard Shore</name>
				<biography>	
					Howard Leslie Shore OC (born October 18, 1946) is a Canadian composer, conductor and orchestrator noted for his film scores. He has composed the scores for over 80 films, most notably the scores for The Lord of the Rings and The Hobbit film trilogies. He won three Academy Awards for his work on The Lord of the Rings, with one being for the song "Into the West", an award he shared with Eurythmics lead vocalist Annie Lennox and writer/producer Fran Walsh, who wrote the lyrics. He is a consistent collaborator with director David Cronenberg, having scored all but one of his films since 1979, and collaborated with Martin Scorsese on six of his films. Shore has also composed a few concert works including one opera, The Fly, based on the plot of Cronenberg's 1986 film, which premiered at the Théâtre du Châtelet in Paris on July 2, 2008; a short piece named Fanfare for the Wanamaker Organ and the Philadelphia Orchestra; and a short overture for the Swiss 21st Century Symphony Orchestra. Shore has also composed for television, including serving as the original musical director for the American sketch comedy show Saturday Night Live from 1975 to 1980. In addition to his three Academy Awards, Shore has also won three Golden Globe Awards and four Grammy Awards.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Elijah Wood</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Frodo Baggings</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian McKellen</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Gandalf</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name></name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character></character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name></name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character></character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>John Gilbert</name>
				<biography>John Gilbert is a film editor who works primarily in New Zealand. Gilbert has edited 17 feature films as well as television shows and short films. He won the Academy Award for Best Film Editing and the BAFTA Award for Best Editing, among several honors, for Mel Gibson's war drama Hacksaw Ridge (2016). Gilbert had earlier received various accolades for his work on Peter Jackson's The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring (2001), including the Satellite Award for Best Editing and nominations for an Academy Award, a BAFTA Award and an ACE Eddie Award.John Gilbert's first position in film was with Government filmmaking body The National Film Unit, in his native New Zealand. Gilbert was taking a break from history and anthropology studies at the time, but never returned to university, moving on to Television New Zealand, where he worked as an assistant editor and editor. Gilbert also spent time freelancing as a sound editor.Gilbert's first credit as an editor on a full-length feature was for the film Crush (1992), which was invited to the Cannes Film Festival. Gilbert received a "Best Editing" award from the New Zealand Film and Television Awards for comedy drama film Via Satellite (1998). He received a New Zealand Screen Award for editing The World's Fastest Indian (2005) and reunited with Mel Gibson on the historical drama The Professor and the Madman.Gilbert has been elected to membership in the American Cinema Editors.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Michael Semanick</name>
				<biography>Michael Semanick (born 1963) is an American sound engineer, credited as a sound re-recording mixer. He has won two Academy Awards for Best Sound and has been nominated for nine more in the same category. He has worked on more than 110 films since 1987.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>5.0</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>8.8</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>83</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>898200000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-5" title="John Wick" genre="Action" release_date="2014-10-24" duration="101" rating="PG">
		<plot>
In New York City, John Wick is grieving the death of his wife Helen, who had arranged for him to receive a beagle puppy to help cope with his loss. A few days later, a group of Russian gangsters, led by Iosef Tarasov, accost John at a gas station and fail to intimidate him into selling them his 1969 Boss 429 Mustang.[b] That night, they break into John's home, assault him, kill the puppy, and steal the car. Iosef takes the Mustang to a chop shop to remove its identifying details, but the shop owner, Aurelio, recognizes it and refuses service. Aurelio informs John that Iosef is the son of Viggo Tarasov, the boss of New York City's Russian mafia.
Upon learning of his son's actions, Viggo berates Iosef for incurring John's wrath. He reveals John was once a hitman in his employ, and was renowned and feared in the criminal underworld as the Baba Yaga, a ruthless, relentless "man of focus, commitment, and sheer will". After John fell in love with Helen, a civilian, Viggo gave him a seemingly impossible task to earn his freedom; he succeeded.
John recovers a concealed stash from his former career that includes weapons and gold coins. He refuses Viggo's attempt to make amends for his son's actions and kills the hit squad subsequently sent to his home. Viggo puts a $2 million bounty on John and enlists his former mentor, Marcus, to kill him. John lodges at the Continental, a luxurious hotel that serves as neutral ground for the underworld and where conducting criminal business is forbidden. Winston, the hotel's owner and John's old friend, informs him that Iosef is at a nightclub called Red Circle. John infiltrates Red Circle and confronts Iosef, but he is attacked by Viggo's henchman Kirill and forced to retreat to the Continental for medical attention.
As John rests, a hitwoman, Ms. Perkins, sneaks into his room. Marcus sees Perkins from an adjacent building and fires a warning shot to alert John, who wakes up and subdues her. Perkins reveals Viggo has doubled the bounty for her to kill John in the hotel and has concealed a high-value stash in a church. John hires another hitman, Harry, to secure Perkins but she kills Harry and escapes.
At the church, John destroys Viggo's cache of cash and extensive blackmail material. When Viggo arrives to assess the damage, John assaults him and his men but is hit by Kirill's car and captured. John tells Viggo he will not stop until Iosef is dead because the puppy gave him hope and a chance to not be alone in his grief for Helen. Marcus again intervenes to save John, who kills Kirill and threatens Viggo into revealing Iosef's location in a safehouse. John assaults the safehouse and kills Iosef. Marcus encourages John to return to his everyday life. Perkins witnesses this and reveals Marcus's duplicity to Viggo, who has him tortured and killed. Viggo calls John to taunt him with the details, drawing him back to the city.
Winston has Perkins executed for breaking the Continental's rules, then informs John that Viggo is preparing to leave the city by helicopter. John races to New York Harbor, where he fights and mortally wounds Viggo. John, resigned to dying from his injuries, watches on his phone a video of Helen telling him they need to go home. He breaks into a nearby animal clinic, treats his wounds, and adopts a pit bull puppy scheduled to be euthanized before beginning to walk home.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company>
					<name>Thunder Road Pictures</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>87Eleven Productions</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>MJW Films</name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name>DefyNite Films</name>
				</company>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>30000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>United States</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Chad Stahelski</name>
				<biography>	
Chad Stahelski (born September 20, 1968) is an American stuntman and film director. He directed the 2014 film John Wick and its three sequels.[1] He has worked as a stuntman, stunt coordinator and second unit director on several films.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Derek Kolstad</name>
				<biography>	
Derek Kolstad (born April 4, 1974) is an American screenwriter and film producer. He is the creator of the John Wick franchise, which began in 2014. He continued to write for the first two sequels of the franchise and is mainly known as a screenwriter of action films and shows. Originally from Madison, Wisconsin, Kolstad attended Edgewood High School of the Sacred Heart and later studied business administration at Taylor University in Indiana. He moved to California at age 24 to pursue screenwriting. He says he started writing films when he was a teenager, but he struggled to find success in Hollywood at first.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Basil Iwanyk</name>
				<biography>	
Basil William Iwanyk (born January 4, 1970) is an American film producer. He is the founder of Thunder Road Films and most known for Sicario, The Town, Greenland and the John Wick franchise. His films have earned more than $2 billion internationally as of 2018. He is of Ukrainian descent.
After starting out working for Warner Bros in the 1990s, Basil founded his own company, Thunder Road, in 2000. The company has a stellar reputation within the industry and a remarkable track record of critical and commercial success.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Leitch</name>
				<biography>David Leitch (born November 16, 1975)[1] is an American filmmaker, actor, stunt performer and stunt coordinator who made his directorial debut on the 2014 action film John Wick with Chad Stahelski, though only Stahelski was credited.[3] Leitch then directed the 2017 thriller film Atomic Blonde, starring Charlize Theron, and 2018's Deadpool 2, the sequel to the 2016 film. In 2019, he directed Hobbs & Shaw, a spin-off of the Fast & Furious franchise, and in 2022 directed Bullet Train, starring Brad Pitt.</biography>				
				<job>Producer</job>			
				</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Tyler Bates</name>
				<biography>	
Tyler Bates (born June 5, 1965 is an American musician,producer, and composer for film, television, and video game scores.Much of his work is in the action and horror film genres, with films like Dawn of the Dead, 300, Sucker Punch, Halloween I and II, and the John Wick franchise. He has collaborated with directors like Zack Snyder, Rob Zombie, Neil Marshall, William Friedkin, Scott Derrickson, James Gunn, Chad Stahelski and David Leitch. In addition, he is also the former lead guitarist of the American rock band Marilyn Manson, and produced its albums The Pale Emperor and Heaven Upside Down. He's currently Jerry Cantrell‘s touring/studio member.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Keanu Reeves</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>John Wick</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Michael Nyqvist</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Viggo Tarasov</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Alfie Allen</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Iosef Tarasov</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian McShane</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Winston</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Lance Reddick</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Charon</character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Elisabet Ronaldsdottir</name>
				<biography>Elísabet Ronaldsdóttir has been working as a film editor since the late 1990s. She often works with directors Baltasar Kormákur and David Leitch. In 2008, 2012 and 2013 she was awarded the Icelandic film award Edda for best editing. Her work includes more than 45 productions. In 2018 she was appointed to the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, which awards the Oscars annually.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Evan J. Haley</name>
				<biography>Evan J Haley received his first taste with audio in 2003 while attending a concert at a local venue. The band was popular, but unsigned, and seemed to need some assistance. You can say that's when his future career in audio took flight. From that day on, Captive8 entrusted him with duties of loading in, loading out, setup, tear-down, trouble shooting all problems, personal musician technician, P.A. equipment setup, microphone placement, and running sound for F.O.H, and Monitor land. Evan always had a good ear, and was able to distinguish what sounded evenly mixed. The band was always very happy, and impressed with his work. Live sound felt as if it was second nature for Evan and he decided to apply for an intern position at the same venue he watched Captive8 perform. Evan worked at the venue every weekend for the next year learning as much as he possibly could about sound. While he worked at the club, Evan had the opportunity to run Monitor Land for all the local, and national acts that performed. While interning at the club he enrolled for school to future his education in all aspects of audio. Evan often found myself in the Pro Tools mixing and recording labs learning as much as he could about multitrack recorders, hardware and software DAW's. He continued to explore the realm of software DAW's discovering how addicting it was to record and mix sessions in Pro Tools. As his eagerness for audio continued, Evan switch his focus from music to motion picture. He set his focus to work with film as a Sound Editor/Sound Designer, and Mixer. Evan live's in Los Angeles, CA living out his dream working on a variety of different projects always striving, and pushing himself to get to the next step in his career.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
				<company>
					<name> </name>
				</company>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.4</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>94</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>86000000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
</movies>
