<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Movies tag represents a list of movies -->
<movies xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="moviesSchema.xsd">
	<movie id="ID-1" title="Harry Potter And The Philosopher Stone" release_date="2001-11-04" duration="152" rating="PG">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Fantasy"/>
			<genre type="Adventure"/>
		</genres>
		<plot>	
				Late one night, Albus Dumbledore and Minerva McGonagall, professors at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, along with groundskeeper Rubeus Hagrid, deliver an orphaned infant wizard named Harry Potter to his Muggle aunt and uncle, Petunia and Vernon Dursley, his only living relatives.
				Ten years later, just before Harry's eleventh birthday, owls begin delivering letters addressed to him. When the abusive Dursleys adamantly refuse to allow Harry to open any and flee to an island hut, Hagrid arrives to personally deliver Harry's letter of acceptance to Hogwarts. Hagrid also reveals that Harry's parents, James and Lily, were killed by a dark wizard named Lord Voldemort. The killing curse that Voldemort had cast towards Harry rebounded, destroying Voldemort's body and giving Harry his lightning-bolt scar. Hagrid then takes Harry to Diagon Alley for school supplies and gives him a pet snowy owl whom he names Hedwig. Harry buys a wand that is connected to Voldemort's own wand.
				At King's Cross station, Harry boards the Hogwarts Express train, and meets fellow students Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger during the journey. Arriving at Hogwarts, Harry also meets Draco Malfoy, who is from a wealthy wizard family; the two immediately form a rivalry. The students assemble in the Great Hall where the Sorting Hat sorts the first-years into four respective houses: Gryffindor, Hufflepuff, Ravenclaw, and Slytherin. Harry is placed into Gryffindor alongside Ron and Hermione, while Draco is placed into Slytherin, a house noted for dark wizards.
				As he studies magic, Harry learns more about his parents and Voldemort, and his natural talent for broomstick flying gets him recruited for the Gryffindor Quidditch team as the youngest Seeker in a century. While returning to the Gryffindor common room, the staircases change paths, leading Harry, Ron and Hermione to the third floor, which is forbidden to students. There they discover a giant three-headed dog named Fluffy. On Halloween, Ron insults Hermione after she shows off in Charms class; upset, she spends the entire afternoon crying in the girls' bathroom. That evening, a giant marauding troll enters it, but Harry and Ron save Hermione, and they make up and become close friends after Hermione takes the blame for the incident by claiming she went looking for the troll.
				The trio discover that Fluffy is guarding the philosopher's stone, a magical object that can turn metal into gold and produce an immortality elixir. Harry suspects that Potions teacher and head of Slytherin House, Severus Snape, wants the stone to return Voldemort to physical form. When Hagrid accidentally reveals that music puts Fluffy asleep, Harry, Ron and Hermione decide to find the stone before Snape. Fluffy is already asleep, but the trio face other barriers, including a deadly plant called Devil's Snare, a room filled with aggressive flying keys, and a giant chess game that knocks out Ron.
				After overcoming the barriers, Harry encounters Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher Quirinus Quirrell who wants the stone; Snape had figured it out and had been protecting Harry. Quirrell removes his turban to reveal a weakened Voldemort living on the back of his head. Dumbledore's protective enchantment places the stone in Harry's possession. Voldemort attempts to bargain the stone from Harry in exchange for resurrecting his parents, but Harry sees through his trick and refuses. Quirrell attempts to kill Harry. When Harry touches Quirrell's skin, it burns Quirrell, reducing him to ashes. Voldemort's soul rises from the pile and escapes, knocking out Harry as it passes through him.
				Harry recovers in the school infirmary. Dumbledore tells him the stone has been destroyed to prevent misuse, and that Ron and Hermione are safe. He also reveals how Harry defeated Quirrell: when Lily died to save Harry, a love-based protection against Voldemort was placed on him. At the end-of-school-year feast, Harry, Ron, and Hermione are rewarded extra house points for their heroism, tying Gryffindor for first place with Slytherin; Dumbledore then awards ten points to their housemate Neville Longbottom for having had the courage to stand up to the trio, granting Gryffindor the House Cup. Harry returns to the Dursleys for the summer, happy to finally have a real home at Hogwarts. 
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Warner Bros. Pictures"/>
				<company name="Heyday Films"/>
				<company name="1492 Pictures"/>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>125000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United Kingdom">
					<cities>Northumberland, County Durham,  North Yorkshire, London, Hertfordshire, Wiltshire</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Chris Colombus</name>
				<biography>	
							Chris Joseph Columbus(born September 10, 1958) is an American filmmaker. Born in Spangler, Pennsylvania, Columbus studied film at Tisch School of the Arts where he developed an interest in filmmaking. After writing screenplays for several teen comedies in the mid-1980s, he made his directorial debut with a teen adventure, Adventures in Babysitting (1987). Columbus gained recognition soon after with the highly successful Christmas comedy Home Alone (1990) and its sequel Home Alone 2: Lost in New York (1992).
							The comedy Mrs. Doubtfire (1993), starring Robin Williams, was another box office success for Columbus. He went on to direct several other films throughout the 1990s, which were mostly met with lukewarm reception. However, he found commercial success again for directing the film adaptations of J. K. Rowling's novels, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (2001) and its sequel, Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (2002), which are his highest-grossing films to date. In addition to directing, Columbus was a producer for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (2004), and the drama The Help (2011). He also directed the fantasy Percy Jackson and the Olympians: The Lightning Thief (2010) and the 3D action comedy Pixels (2015).
							Columbus is the co-founder of 1492 Pictures, a film production company that has produced some of his films since 1995. More recently, he co-founded another production firm with his daughter in 2014, called Maiden Voyage Pictures. In 2017, he launched ZAG Animation Studios, alongside Michael Barnathan, Haim Saban, and Jeremy Zag. Columbus is also known for his collaboration with composer John Williams, with whom he had worked on the films Home Alone and Harry Potter. 
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Steve Kloves</name>
				<biography>Stephen Keith Kloves(born March 18, 1960) is an American filmmaker. He wrote and directed the 1989 film The Fabulous Baker Boys and is mainly known for his adaptations of novels, especially for all but one of the Harry Potter films (the exception being Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix) and for Wonder Boys, for which he was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay. </biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Joanne Kathleen Rowling</name>
				<biography>	
							Joanne Rowling CH OBE FRSL (born 31 July 1965), best known by her pen name J. K. Rowling, is a British author and philanthropist. She wrote Harry Potter, a seven-volume fantasy series published from 1997 to 2007. The series has sold over 600 million copies, been translated into 84 languages, and spawned a global media franchise including films and video games. The Casual Vacancy (2012) was her first novel for adults. She writes Cormoran Strike, an ongoing crime fiction series, under the alias Robert Galbraith.
							Born in Yate, Gloucestershire, Rowling was working as a researcher and bilingual secretary for Amnesty International in 1990 when she conceived the idea for the Harry Potter series while on a delayed train from Manchester to London. The seven-year period that followed saw the death of her mother, the birth of her first child, divorce from her first husband, and relative poverty until the first novel in the series, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, was published in 1997. Six sequels followed, and by 2008, Forbes had named her the world's highest-paid author.
							Rowling concluded the Harry Potter series with Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows (2007). The novels follow a boy called Harry Potter as he attends Hogwarts (a school for wizards), and battles Lord Voldemort. Death and the divide between good and evil are the central themes of the series. Its influences include Bildungsroman (the coming-of-age genre), school stories, fairy tales, and Christian allegory. The series revived fantasy as a genre in the children's market, spawned a host of imitators, and inspired an active fandom. Critical reception has been more mixed. Many reviewers see Rowling's writing as conventional; some regard her portrayal of gender and social division as regressive. There were also religious debates over the Harry Potter series.
							Rowling has won many accolades for her work. She has received an OBE and made a Companion of Honour for services to literature and philanthropy. Harry Potter brought her wealth and recognition, which she has used to advance philanthropic endeavours and political causes. She co-founded the charity Lumos and established the Volant Charitable Trust, named after her mother. Rowling's charitable giving centres on medical causes and supporting at-risk women and children. In politics, she has donated to Britain's Labour Party and opposed Scottish independence and Brexit. She has publicly expressed her opinions on transgender people and related civil rights since 2017. These have been criticised as transphobic by LGBT rights organisations and some feminists, but have received support from other feminists and individuals.  
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Heyman</name>
				<biography>David Jonathan Heyman (born 26 July 1961) is a British film producer and the founder of Heyday Films. Heyman is best known as the primary producer of all eight installments of the Harry Potter film series, which are based on a series of popular fantasy novels of the same name by author J. K. Rowling. He then produced all three installments of its spin-off prequel series, Fantastic Beasts. His work makes him the second-most commercially successful producer of all time.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-9" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>John Williams</name>
				<biography>	
							John Towner Williams (born February 8, 1932) is an American composer, conductor, and pianist. In a career that has spanned seven decades, he has composed some of the most popular, recognizable and critically acclaimed film scores in cinema history. Williams has won 25 Grammy Awards, five Academy Awards, seven British Academy Film Awards, and four Golden Globe Awards. With 53 Academy Award nominations, he is the second most-nominated individual, after only Walt Disney. His compositions are considered the epitome of film music, and he is considered among the greatest composers in the history of cinema.Williams has composed many of his film scoring works for frequent collaborators Steven Spielberg and George Lucas, and other directors such as Chris Columbus, Oliver Stone, Richard Donner, Irvin Kershner, Sydney Pollack, Alfred Hitchcock, Mark Rydell, Mark Robson, Jean-Jacques Annaud, Robert Altman, and J. J. Abrams. He has a very distinct and recognizable sound that mixes romanticism, impressionism and atonal music with complex orchestration.
							Williams has been associated with director Steven Spielberg since 1974, composing music for all but five of his feature films, and George Lucas, with whom he has worked on both of his main franchises, Star Wars and Indiana Jones. His early work as a film composer includes The Killers (1964), How to Steal a Million (1966), Valley of the Dolls (1967), and Goodbye Mr. Chips (1969). He has received five Academy Awards for Best Original Score for his work on Fiddler on the Roof (1971), Jaws (1975), Star Wars (1977), E.T.: The Extra Terrestrial (1982), and Schindler's List (1993). Williams has composed for many popular films including the Star Wars saga, Superman, the first two Home Alone films, the Indiana Jones films, the first two Jurassic Park films, and the first three Harry Potter films. Other memorable film scores from his collaboration with Spielberg include Close Encounters of the Third Kind (1977), Hook (1991), Saving Private Ryan (1998), Catch Me If You Can (2002), War of the Worlds (2005), War Horse (2011), Lincoln (2012), and The Fabelmans (2022).
							Williams has also composed numerous classical concertos and other works for orchestral ensembles and solo instruments. He served as the Boston Pops' principal conductor from 1980 to 1993 and is its laureate conductor.Other works by Williams include theme music for the 1984 Summer Olympic Games, NBC Sunday Night Football, "The Mission" theme used by NBC News and Seven News in Australia, the television series Lost in Space and Land of the Giants, and the incidental music for the first season of Gilligan's Island. Williams announced but then rescinded his intention to retire from film score composing after the release of Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny in 2023.
							In 2005, the American Film Institute selected Williams's score to 1977's Star Wars as the greatest film score of all time. The Library of Congress entered the Star Wars soundtrack into the National Recording Registry for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant". Williams was inducted into the Hollywood Bowl's Hall of Fame in 2000, and he received a Kennedy Center Honor in 2004. His AFI Life Achievement Award in 2016 was the first to be awarded outside of the acting and directing fields. He has composed the score for nine of the top 25 highest-grossing films at the U.S. box office (adjusted for inflation). His work has influenced other composers of film, popular, and contemporary classical music.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Daniel Radcliffe</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Harry Potter</character>
					<character_description>An 11-year-old orphan living with his unwelcoming aunt, uncle, and cousin, who learns of his own fame as a wizard known to have survived his parents' murder at the hands of the dark wizard Lord Voldemort as an infant when he is accepted to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. Columbus had wanted Radcliffe for the role since he saw him in the BBC's production of David Copperfield, before the open casting sessions had taken place, but had been told by casting director Susan Figgis that Radcliffe's protective parents would not allow their son to take the part. Columbus explained that his persistence in giving Radcliffe the role was responsible for Figgis' resignation. Radcliffe was asked to audition in 2000, when Heyman and Kloves met him and his parents at a production of Stones in His Pockets in London. Heyman and Columbus successfully managed to convince Radcliffe's parents that their son would be protected from media intrusion, and they agreed to let him play Harry. Rowling approved of Radcliffe's casting, stating that "having seen his screen test I don't think Chris Columbus could have found a better Harry." Radcliffe was reportedly paid £1 million for the film, although he felt the fee was "not that important" to him. The Saunders triplets appear as Harry as a baby.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Emma Watson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Hermione Granger</character>
					<character_description>Harry's other best friend and the trio's brains. Watson's Oxford theatre teacher passed her name on to the casting agents and she had to do over five interviews before she got the part. Watson took her audition seriously, but "never really thought she had any chance of getting the role." The producers were impressed by Watson's self-confidence and she outperformed the thousands of other girls who had applied.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Rupert Grint</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Ron Wealsey</character>
					<character_description>Harry's best friend at Hogwarts and a younger member of the Weasley wizarding family. A fan of the series, Grint decided he would be perfect for the part "because he has ginger hair". Having seen a Newsround report about the open casting he sent in a video of himself rapping about how he wished to receive the part. His attempt was successful as the casting team asked for a meeting with him.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian Hart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Professor Quirrell</character>
					<character_description>The stuttering Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher at Hogwarts</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian Hart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Lord Voldemort</character>
					<character_description>Voldemort, an anagrammatic sobriquet for Tom Marvolo Riddle, is the archenemy of Harry Potter, who according to a prophecy has "the power to vanquish the Dark Lord". He attempts to murder the boy, but instead kills his parents, Lily and James Potter, and leaves Harry with a scar on his forehead in the shape of a lightning bolt. Nearly every witch or wizard dares not utter his name and refers to him instead with such monikers as "You-Know-Who", "He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named", or "The Dark Lord". Voldemort's obsession with blood purity signifies his aim to rid the wizarding world of Muggle (non-magical) heritage and to conquer both worlds, Muggle and wizarding, to achieve pure-blood dominance. Through his mother's family, he is the last descendant of the wizard Salazar Slytherin, one of the four founders of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. He is the leader of the Death Eaters, a group of evil wizards and witches dedicated to ridding the Wizarding World of Muggles and establishing Voldemort as its supreme ruler. </character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Alan Rickman</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Severus Snape</character>
					<character_description>The Potions Master and head of Slytherin House.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Richard Harris</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Albus Dumbledore</character>
					<character_description>Hogwarts' Headmaster and one of the most famous and powerful wizards of all time. Harris initially rejected the role, only to reverse his decision after his granddaughter stated she would never speak to him again if he did not take it.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Tom Felton</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Draco Malfoy</character>
					<character_description>A student in Slytherin and Harry's rival.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard Francis-Bruce</name>
				<biography>Richard Leslie Francis-Bruce AM (born 10 December 1948) is an Australian film editor who has received several nominations for the Academy Award for Best Film Editing. </biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-2" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>John A. Midgley</name>
				<biography>John Midgley is an English sound engineer. He won an Oscar in the category Best Sound Mixing for Hugo and has been nominated for another two. He has worked on more than 100 films since 1977.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company name="Warner Bros. Pictures"/>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Warner Bros. Pictures"/>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Warner Bros. Pictures"/>
			</distribution_company>
			<streaming_services>
				<company name="Peacock"/>
				<company name="Prime Video"/>
				<company name="Max"/>
			</streaming_services>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.8</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.6</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>81</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>1024254401</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-2" title="Green Mile" release_date="1999-12-10" duration="189" rating="PG-13">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Drama" />
			<genre type="Fantasy" />
			<genre type="Supernatural"/>
		</genres>
		<plot>
				At a Louisiana assisted-living home in 1999, retiree Paul Edgecomb begins to cry while watching the film Top Hat. His companion Elaine becomes concerned, and Paul explains to her that the film reminded him of events that he witnessed when he was an officer at Cold Mountain Penitentiary's death row, nicknamed "The Green Mile".
				In 1935, Paul supervised Corrections Officers Brutus "Brutal" Howell, Dean Stanton, Harry Terwilliger, and Percy Wetmore, reporting to Warden Hal Moores. Percy, the nephew of the state governor's wife, demonstrates a severe sadistic streak but flaunts his family connections to avoid being held accountable. He is particularly abusive towards prisoner Eduard "Del" Delacroix, breaking his fingers and killing his pet mouse, Mr. Jingles.
				Paul is introduced to John Coffey, a physically imposing but mild-mannered black man sentenced to death after being convicted of raping and murdering two young white girls. He joins Del and another condemned convict: Arlen Bitterbuck, the first to be executed. The officers are forced to deal with psychotic new inmate William "Wild Bill" Wharton, who frequently causes trouble by assaulting the officers and racially abusing John, forcing them to restrain him in the block's padded cell on more than one occasion.
				After John heals Paul's severe bladder infection by touching him, and later resurrects Mr. Jingles, Paul gradually realizes that John possesses a supernatural ability to heal others. Paul doubts whether someone with the power to perform divine miracles is truly guilty of the crime.
				In exchange for resigning from the penitentiary and accepting a job at an insane asylum, Percy is allowed to oversee Del's execution. At the execution, Percy deliberately avoids soaking the sponge used to conduct electricity to Del's head, leading to Del suffering a gruesome and agonizing death by burning, with John forced to feel Del's pain as well. Paul and the other officers punish Percy by forcing him to spend a night in the padded cell. While Percy is locked away, they drug Wharton and secretly smuggle John out of the prison so that he can use his powers to heal Warden Moores' wife Melinda of a brain tumor, saving her life. After Percy is released from the padded room, the others threaten to report him for his various acts of misconduct if his behavior continues.
				John uses his powers to "release" Melinda's affliction into Percy's brain, causing Percy to shoot Wharton dead. Soon after, John reveals in a vision to Paul that Wharton was the true culprit of the crimes for which he was wrongfully condemned, releasing his supernatural energy into Paul in the process. Having gone into a catatonic state, Percy is committed to the same insane asylum where he had planned to work after resigning from the prison.
				After realizing that John is innocent, Paul becomes distraught at the thought of executing him and offers to let him go free. John tells Paul that the execution would be an act of mercy, as he views the world as a cruel place and is in constant pain from the suffering that people inflict upon each other. Mentioning that he has never seen a movie before, John watches Top Hat with the other officers as his last request. As John is taken to be executed, he is mercilessly scorned by the parents of the two girls who still believe him to be guilty. He asks not to have a hood placed over his head as he is afraid of the dark. Paul, Brutal, and the officers watch in great sadness, visibly holding back tears as John is executed.
				Back in present day, Paul tells Elaine that John's execution was the last that he and Brutal witnessed, as they both subsequently resigned from the prison and took jobs in the juvenile system. Paul reveals to Elaine that Mr. Jingles is still alive, having been blessed with a supernaturally long life thanks to John's healing touch. He also reveals that he is now 108 years old; he was 44 when John was executed. While Elaine sees Paul's long life as another of John's miracles, Paul speculates that he may have been condemned to linger on Earth and outlive all of his loved ones as a divine punishment for John's execution. Paul later attends Elaine's funeral and muses on how much longer he has left to live, saying, "We each owe a death. There are no exceptions. But, oh, God... sometimes, the Green Mile seems so long."
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Castle Rock Entertainment"/>
				<company name="Darkwoods Productions"/>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>60000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United States of America">
					<cities>California, Shelbyville, Tennessee, North Carolina</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>	
					Frank Arpad Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959) is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007).
					Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).	
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>Frank Arpad Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959) is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007). Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Frank Darabont</name>
				<biography>Frank Arpad Darabont (born Ferenc Árpád Darabont, January 28, 1959) is a French-born American filmmaker. He has been nominated for three Academy Awards and a Golden Globe Award. In his early career, he was primarily a screenwriter for such horror films as A Nightmare on Elm Street 3: Dream Warriors (1987), The Blob (1988) and The Fly II (1989). As a director, he is known for his film adaptations of Stephen King novellas and novels, such as The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Green Mile (1999), and The Mist (2007).Darabont also developed and executive-produced the first season and first half of the second season of the AMC horror series The Walking Dead (2010–2011).</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Valdes</name>
				<biography>David Valdes (born August 12, 1950, in Los Angeles) is an American film producer known for working in the western genre and collaborating with Clint Eastwood. His first production experience was as a guest on a film called Diary of a Mad Housewife, which was shot in his hometown in 1969.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Thomas Newman</name>
				<biography>	
					Thomas Montgomery Newman (born October 20, 1955) is an American composer and conductor best known for his many film scores. In a career that has spanned over four decades, he has scored numerous films including The Player (1992), The Shawshank Redemption (1994), The Horse Whisperer (1998), American Beauty and The Green Mile (both 1999), In the Bedroom (2001), Road to Perdition and White Oleander (both 2002), Finding Nemo (2003), Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events (2004), Cinderella Man (2005), WALL-E (2008), the James Bond films Skyfall (2012) and Spectre (2015), Finding Dory (2016), 1917 (2019), and Elemental (2023). He also composed the music for the 2003 HBO miniseries Angels in America. Throughout his career, he has collaborated extensively with directors such as Sam Mendes, Andrew Stanton, Frank Darabont, Steven Soderbergh, Jon Avnet, John Madden and John Lee Hancock.
					Newman has been nominated for fifteen Academy Awards, tying him with fellow composer Alex North for the most nominations without a win. He has also been nominated for four Golden Globes, and has won two BAFTAs, six Grammys and an Emmy Award. Newman was honored with the Richard Kirk award at the 2000 BMI Film and TV Awards. The award is given annually to a composer who has made significant contributions to film and television music. His achievements have contributed to the Newmans being the most nominated Academy Award extended family, with a collective 92 nominations in various music categories.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Tom Hanks</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Paul Edgecomb</character>
					<character_description>Paul Edgecomb is the commanding officer of the death row cellblock at Cold Mountain Penitentiary in Louisiana in 1932 (novel) or 1935 (movie adaptation). He is married to Jan Edgecomb and is a father and a decent man. Though he doesn't care for his position, the Depression dictates that he make the best of an unpleasant task. He watches out for his fellow guards and does what he can for the condemned men. He runs a quiet and neat operation. He befriends John Coffey. When he realizes that John has the ability to cure people he has John cure Melinda Moores, Warden Hal Moores' wife. He is unable to stop John's execution though, which causes him great sadness. He lives in excess of 100 years due to the fact that John passes on a bit of his grace to him when curing Paul of a bladder infection. Paul speculates that it's a curse from God for allowing one of God's chosen to die in such a terrible manner.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>David Morse</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Brutus Howell</character>
					<character_description>Brutus Howell is a character in the novel The Green Mile. He is a guard at Cold Mountain Penitentiary on death row and the second in command there. He is loyal to Paul Edgecomb and hates Percy Wetmore as much as Paul.  Despite his nickname and his size, Brutus rarely hurts the inmates and is rather soft-hearted, although his temper is rather short.However, Brutus cannot put up with disrespect and is furious when Percy mistreats the inmates. This is shown a few times throughout the movie, such as when Percy degrades Bitterbuck's body, when he says that the Green Mile is just "a bucket of piss to drown rats in" (thus referring to the inmates as "rats"), and when Percy botches Del's execution. After Percy does the latter, Brutal loses his temper and punches Percy, but Paul holds him back. He was one of the guards who attends John coffey's execution. In the book, he died 25 years later, 1960, of a sudden heart-attack while eating a fish sandwich and watching wrestling T.V.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Michael Clarke Duncan</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>John Coffey</character>
					<character_description>John Coffey is a supporting character of the Stephen King multiverse, serving as the deuteragonist of the novel The Green Mile and its film adaptation of the same name.He was an innocent inmate placed on death row at Cold Mountain Penitentiary for a crime he never committed.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Sam Rockwell</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Wild Bill</character>
					<character_description>William "Wild Bill" Wharton is the main antagonist of the novel The Green Mile by Stephen King and its 1999 film adaptation. He is a wild-acting, dangerous multiple-murderer who is determined to make as much trouble as he can before he is executed. He is also responsible for killing a family, raping two kids, and framing John Coffey for it. He was also the arch-nemesis of John Coffey.He was portrayed by Sam Rockwell, who also portrayed Eric Knox in Charlie's Angels, Zaphod Beeblebrox in The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy, Justin Hammer in the Marvel Cinematic Universe, Billy Bickle in Seven Psychopaths, Randy Borland in Law And Order, Mortimer Ramsey in Dishonored 2, Jason Dixon in Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri and Mr. Wolf in The Bad Guys.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Patricia Clarkson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Melinda Moores</character>
					<character_description>Melinda Moore is the wife of Cold Mountain Penitentiary warden Hal Moores. She has an end stage Cancer and is in a great deal of pain. Paul Edgecomb arranges, that John Coffey goes to her so that he can cure her, which he does.She gives John her St. Christopher cross in gratitude for what he did.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Bonnie Hunt</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Jan Engecomb</character>
					<character_description>She is the wife of Paul Edgecomb. They have been married for many years and their children are grown and moved out when the story begins. She and Paul have a good marriage and they are very tight. Sadly, she dies before Paul.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard Francis-Bruce</name>
				<biography>Richard Leslie Francis-Bruce AM (born 10 December 1948) is an Australian film editor who has received several nominations for the Academy Award for Best Film Editing. </biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-1" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Robert J. Litt</name>
				<biography>Litt is an American sound engineer. He was nominated for three Academy Awards in the category Best Sound. He worked on over 160 films between 1964 and 2000.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Paulette Osorio"/>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Warner Bros"/>
				<company name="Universal Pictures"/>
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.0</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>8.6</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>79</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>286800000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-3" title="Titanic" release_date="1997-11-01" duration="195" rating="G">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Romance"/>
			<genre type="Drama"/>
		</genres>
		<plot>
				In 1996, aboard the research vessel Akademik Mstislav Keldysh, Brock Lovett and his team search the wreck of RMS Titanic. They recover a safe they hope contains a necklace with a large diamond known as the Heart of the Ocean. Instead, they find only a drawing of a young nude woman wearing the necklace. The sketch is dated April 14, 1912, the same day the Titanic struck the iceberg that caused it to sink. After viewing a television news story about the discovery, centenarian Rose Dawson Calvert contacts Lovett, identifying herself as the woman in the drawing. Hoping she can help locate the necklace, Lovett brings Rose aboard Keldysh, where she recounts her experiences as a Titanic passenger.
				In 1912 Southampton, 17-year-old Rose DeWitt Bukater, her wealthy fiancé Caledon "Cal" Hockley and Rose's widowed mother Ruth board the Titanic. Ruth emphasizes that Rose's marrying Cal will resolve the family's financial problems and maintain their upper-class status. Meanwhile, Jack Dawson, a poor young artist, wins a third-class Titanic ticket in a poker game. After setting sail, Rose, distraught over her loveless engagement, climbs over the stern railing, intending to commit suicide. Jack coaxes her back onto the deck and they develop a friendship. Jack soon admits that he has feelings for Rose. When Cal and Ruth object, Rose rejects Jack's attentions, but returns to him after realizing she has fallen in love.
				Rose brings Jack to her state room and requests he draw her nude, wearing only the Heart of the Ocean. They later evade Cal's servant, Lovejoy, and have sex in a Renault Towncar inside the cargo hold. On the forward deck, they witness the ship's collision with an iceberg and overhear its officers discussing its seriousness. Cal discovers Jack's sketch and an insulting note from Rose in his safe, along with the necklace. When Jack and Rose return to warn the others about the collision, Cal has Lovejoy slip the necklace into Jack's pocket to frame him for theft. Jack is confined in the master-at-arms' office. Cal puts the necklace into his own overcoat pocket.
				With the ship sinking, the crew prioritize women and children for evacuation. Rose finds and frees Jack, and they make it back to the deck, where Cal and Jack urge Rose to board a lifeboat. Intending to save himself, Cal lies that he will get Jack safely off the ship and wraps his overcoat around Rose. As her lifeboat is lowered, Rose, unable to abandon Jack, jumps back onto the ship. Cal grabs Lovejoy's pistol and chases Jack and Rose, but they escape. Cal realizes the necklace is still in the coat he gave Rose. He poses as a lost child's father to board a lifeboat.
				Jack and Rose return to the deck. The ship's stern is rising as the flooded bow sinks; the two desperately cling to the stern rail. The upended ship breaks in half and the bow section sinks. The stern slams back onto the ocean, upends again and sinks. In the freezing water, Jack helps Rose onto a wood transom panel among the debris, buoyant enough only for one person, and makes her promise to survive. Jack dies of cold shock, but Rose is among six people saved by the one returning lifeboat. RMS Carpathia rescues the survivors. Rose avoids Cal and her mother by hiding among the steerage passengers and giving her name as Rose Dawson. Still wearing Cal's overcoat, she discovers the necklace tucked inside the pocket.
				In the present, Rose says she heard that Cal committed suicide after losing his fortune in the Wall Street Crash of 1929. Lovett abandons his search after hearing Rose's story. Alone on the stern of Keldysh, Rose takes the Heart of the Ocean, which has been in her possession all along, and drops it into the sea over the wreck site. While she is seemingly asleep in her bed, her photos on the dresser depict a life of freedom and adventure inspired by Jack. A young Rose reunites with Jack at the Titanic's Grand Staircase, applauded by those who died that night.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Paramount Pictures"/>
				<company name="20th Century Studios"/>
				<company name="Lightstorm Entertainment"/>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>200000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="Mexico">
					<cities>Rosarito Beach</cities>
				</country>
				<country name="Canada">
					<cities>Nova Scotia</cities>
				</country>
				<country name="United States of America">
					<cities>California</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>James Cameron</name>
				<biography>	
					James Francis Cameron CC (born August 16, 1954) is a Canadian filmmaker. A major figure in the post-New Hollywood era, Cameron is considered one of the industry's most innovative filmmakers, regularly making use of novel technologies. He first gained recognition for writing and directing The Terminator (1984) and found further success with Aliens (1986), The Abyss (1989), Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991), and the action comedy True Lies (1994). He wrote and directed Titanic (1997), Avatar (2009) and its sequels, with Titanic earning him Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Film Editing. A recipient of various other industry accolades, two of his films have been selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library of Congress.
					Cameron co-founded the production companies Lightstorm Entertainment, Digital Domain, and Earthship Productions. In addition to filmmaking, he is a National Geographic sea tourist and has produced many documentaries on the subject, including Ghosts of the Abyss (2003) and Aliens of the Deep (2005). Cameron has also contributed to underwater filming and remote vehicle technologies and helped create the digital 3D Fusion Camera System. In 2012, Cameron became the first person to do a solo descent to the bottom of the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth's ocean, in the Deepsea Challenger submersible.
					Cameron's films have grossed over $8 billion worldwide, making him the second-highest-grossing film director of all time. Three of Cameron's films are amongst the top four highest-grossing films of all time; Avatar (2009), Avatar: The Way of Water (2022) and Titanic (1997) are the highest, third-highest and fourth-highest-grossing films of all time, respectively. Cameron directed the first film to gross over $1 billion, the first two films to gross over $2 billion, and is the only director to have had three films gross over $2 billion. In 2010, Time named Cameron one of the 100 most influential people in the world. Cameron is also an environmentalist and runs several sustainability businesses.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>James Cameron</name>
				<biography>	
					James Francis Cameron CC (born August 16, 1954) is a Canadian filmmaker. A major figure in the post-New Hollywood era, Cameron is considered one of the industry's most innovative filmmakers, regularly making use of novel technologies. He first gained recognition for writing and directing The Terminator (1984) and found further success with Aliens (1986), The Abyss (1989), Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991), and the action comedy True Lies (1994). He wrote and directed Titanic (1997), Avatar (2009) and its sequels, with Titanic earning him Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Film Editing. A recipient of various other industry accolades, two of his films have been selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library of Congress.
					Cameron co-founded the production companies Lightstorm Entertainment, Digital Domain, and Earthship Productions. In addition to filmmaking, he is a National Geographic sea tourist and has produced many documentaries on the subject, including Ghosts of the Abyss (2003) and Aliens of the Deep (2005). Cameron has also contributed to underwater filming and remote vehicle technologies and helped create the digital 3D Fusion Camera System. In 2012, Cameron became the first person to do a solo descent to the bottom of the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth's ocean, in the Deepsea Challenger submersible.
					Cameron's films have grossed over $8 billion worldwide, making him the second-highest-grossing film director of all time. Three of Cameron's films are amongst the top four highest-grossing films of all time; Avatar (2009), Avatar: The Way of Water (2022) and Titanic (1997) are the highest, third-highest and fourth-highest-grossing films of all time, respectively. Cameron directed the first film to gross over $1 billion, the first two films to gross over $2 billion, and is the only director to have had three films gross over $2 billion. In 2010, Time named Cameron one of the 100 most influential people in the world. Cameron is also an environmentalist and runs several sustainability businesses.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>James Cameron</name>
				<biography>	
					James Francis Cameron CC (born August 16, 1954) is a Canadian filmmaker. A major figure in the post-New Hollywood era, Cameron is considered one of the industry's most innovative filmmakers, regularly making use of novel technologies. He first gained recognition for writing and directing The Terminator (1984) and found further success with Aliens (1986), The Abyss (1989), Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991), and the action comedy True Lies (1994). He wrote and directed Titanic (1997), Avatar (2009) and its sequels, with Titanic earning him Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Film Editing. A recipient of various other industry accolades, two of his films have been selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library of Congress.
					Cameron co-founded the production companies Lightstorm Entertainment, Digital Domain, and Earthship Productions. In addition to filmmaking, he is a National Geographic sea tourist and has produced many documentaries on the subject, including Ghosts of the Abyss (2003) and Aliens of the Deep (2005). Cameron has also contributed to underwater filming and remote vehicle technologies and helped create the digital 3D Fusion Camera System. In 2012, Cameron became the first person to do a solo descent to the bottom of the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth's ocean, in the Deepsea Challenger submersible.
					Cameron's films have grossed over $8 billion worldwide, making him the second-highest-grossing film director of all time. Three of Cameron's films are amongst the top four highest-grossing films of all time; Avatar (2009), Avatar: The Way of Water (2022) and Titanic (1997) are the highest, third-highest and fourth-highest-grossing films of all time, respectively. Cameron directed the first film to gross over $1 billion, the first two films to gross over $2 billion, and is the only director to have had three films gross over $2 billion. In 2010, Time named Cameron one of the 100 most influential people in the world. Cameron is also an environmentalist and runs several sustainability businesses.
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Jon Landau</name>
				<biography>Jon Landau (born July 23, 1960) is an American film producer, known for producing Titanic (1997), a film which won him an Oscar and earned $2.19 billion in gross revenues, as well as Avatar (2009) and Avatar: The Way of Water (2022), which earned $2.9 billion and $2.2 billion respectively. As of 2023, these are three of the four highest-grossing films of all time.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>James Horner</name>
				<biography>	
					James Roy Horner (August 14, 1953 – June 22, 2015) was an American composer of film scores. He worked on over 160 film and television productions between 1978 and 2015, and was the winner of two Academy Awards, among many other accolades. He was known for the integration of choral and electronic elements alongside traditional orchestrations, and for his use of motifs associated with Celtic music.
					Horner won two Academy Awards for James Cameron's Titanic (1997), for which he composed the best-selling orchestral film soundtrack of all time. He also wrote the score for the highest-grossing film of all time, Cameron's Avatar. Horner's other Oscar-nominated scores were for Aliens (1986), An American Tail (1986), Field of Dreams (1989), Apollo 13 (1995), Braveheart (1995), A Beautiful Mind (2001), and House of Sand and Fog (2003). Horner's other notable scores include Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan (1982), Willow (1988), The Land Before Time (1988), Glory (1989), The Rocketeer (1991), Legends of the Fall (1994), Jumanji (1995), The Mask of Zorro (1998), How the Grinch Stole Christmas (2000), Troy (2004), The New World (2005), Apocalypto (2006), and The Karate Kid (2010).
					Horner collaborated on multiple projects with directors including Don Bluth, James Cameron, Jean-Jacques Annaud, Joe Johnston, Walter Hill, Mel Gibson, Vadim Perelman, Ron Howard, Edward Zwick, Nicholas Meyer, Wolfgang Petersen, Martin Campbell, Phil Nibbelink and Simon Wells; producers including George Lucas, David Kirschner, Lawrence Gordon, Jon Landau, Brian Grazer and Steven Spielberg; and songwriters including Will Jennings, Barry Mann and Cynthia Weil. He won two Academy Awards; Best Original Score for Titanic and Best Original Song for "My Heart Will Go On", six Grammy Awards, two Golden Globes, and was nominated for three BAFTA Awards.
					Horner, who was an avid pilot, was killed in a single-fatality crash while flying his Short Tucano turboprop aircraft. He was 61 years old. The scores for his final three films, Southpaw (2015), The 33 (2015) and The Magnificent Seven (2016), were all completed and released posthumously.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Leonardo DiCaprio</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Jack Dawson</character>
					<character_description>Jack Dawson is a 20-year old man who won his and Fabrizio de Rossi's third-class tickets on the Titanic in a lucky hand of poker with Olaf and Sven. He has traveled the world since he was 15 and has been to various places such as Paris. He is also a very good artist who drew many paintings, especially of people. Some of these include nude women, in perticular French ladies. Jack later tells Rose that girls in Paris are willing to take their clothes off.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Kate Winslet</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Rose DeWitt BuKater</character>
					<character_description>Rose Dawson Calvert (née DeWitt-Bukater, born 1895) was an American socialite and later actress. She was born in Philadelphia in 1895, but her exact birthdate is unknown.In 1912 she was returning to America aboard the RMS Titanic, with her aristocratic fiancé Caledon Hockley. However, during the voyage she and third-class passenger Jack Dawson fell in love.The voyage came to an abrupt end when the ship struck ice and sank. Rose survived the ship's sinking, but Jack did not.She later married a man named Calvert, and had at least three children.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Billy Zane</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Cadelon Hockley</character>
					<character_description>Caledon Nathan Hockley, often shortened to Cal was an American industrialist and the heir to a Pittsburgh steel fortune.In 1912 he was a first-class passenger aboard the RMS Titanic, accompanying his 17-year-old fiancée Rose DeWitt Bukater. However, during the voyage Rose and third-class passenger Jack Dawson fell in love.The ship struck an iceberg and sank a few days before the date of its intended arrival in New York City. Hockley survived the sinking by cheating his way onto a lifeboat, pretending a deserted child was his own. He lost contact with Rose, mistakenly believing she had died in the sinking.He was later driven to suicide after being bankrupted by the financial crash of 1929.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Kathy Bates</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Molly Brown</character>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Gloria Stuart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Rose DeWitt BuKater</character>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Conrad Buff</name>
				<biography>Conrad Buff IV (born July 8, 1948) is an American film editor with more than 25 film credits since 1985. Buff is known for winning an Academy Award for Best Film Editing and an ACE Eddie Award for Titanic (1997); the awards were shared with his co-editors James Cameron and Richard A. Harris. He won the 2000 Satellite Award for Best Editing for Thirteen Days.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Richard A. Harris</name>
				<biography>Richard A. Harris (born February 6, 1934) is an American film editor with a career spanning nearly forty years. He graduated from the School of Cinematic Arts of the University of Southern California in 1956. He is most associated with the films of Michael Ritchie (Downhill Racer, The Candidate, An Almost Perfect Affair) and James Cameron (Terminator 2: Judgment Day, True Lies).</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Christopher Boyes</name>
				<biography>Christopher Boyes is an American sound engineer. He has won four Academy Awards and has been nominated for another eleven. He has worked on more than 100 films since 1991.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-6 ID-7 ID-8 ID-9" />
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company name="Greg Ferris"/>
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Eileen Peterson"/>
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Tyler Atkinson"/>
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.0</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.9</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>88</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>2257000000000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-4" title="The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring" release_date="1997-11-01" duration="195" rating="PG-13">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Fantasy" />
			<genre type="Action" />
			<genre type="Adventure" />
			<genre type="Drama" />
		</genres>
		<plot>
				In the Second Age of Middle-earth, the lords of Elves, Dwarves, and Men are given Rings of Power. Unbeknownst to them, the Dark Lord Sauron forges the One Ring in 			Mount Doom, instilling into it a great part of his power, to dominate the other Rings and conquer Middle-earth. A final alliance of Men and Elves battles Sauron's 			forces in Mordor. Isildur of Gondor severs Sauron's finger and the Ring with it, thereby vanquishing Sauron and returning him to spirit form. With Sauron's first 			defeat, the Third Age of Middle-earth begins. The Ring's influence corrupts Isildur, who takes it for himself and is later killed by Orcs. The Ring is lost in a 			river for 2,500 years until it is found by Gollum, who owns it for over four and a half centuries. The ring abandons Gollum and it is subsequently found by a hobbit 			named Bilbo Baggins, who is unaware of its history.
				Sixty years later, Bilbo celebrates his 111th birthday in the Shire, reuniting with his old friend, the wizard Gandalf the Grey. Bilbo departs the Shire for one 			last adventure, and he leaves his inheritance, including the Ring, to his nephew Frodo. Gandalf investigates the Ring, discovers its true nature, and learns that 			Gollum was captured and brutally tortured by Sauron's Orcs, revealing two words during his interrogation: "Shire" and "Baggins." Gandalf returns and warns Frodo to 			leave the Shire. As Frodo departs with his friend, gardener Samwise Gamgee, Gandalf rides to Isengard to meet with the wizard Saruman, but discovers his betrayal 			and alliance with Sauron, who has dispatched his nine undead Nazgûl servants to find Frodo.
				Frodo and Sam are joined by fellow hobbits Merry and Pippin, and they evade the Nazgûl before arriving in Bree, where they are meant to meet Gandalf at the Inn of 			The Prancing Pony. However, Gandalf never arrives, having been taken prisoner by Saruman. The hobbits are then aided by a Ranger named Strider, who promises to 			escort them to Rivendell; however, they are ambushed by the Nazgûl on Weathertop, and their leader, the Witch-King, stabs Frodo with a Morgul blade. Arwen, an Elf 			and Strider's beloved, locates Strider and rescues Frodo, summoning flood-waters that sweep the Nazgûl away. She takes him to Rivendell, where he is healed by the 			Elves. Frodo meets with Gandalf, who escaped Isengard on a Great Eagle. That night, Strider reunites with Arwen, and they affirm their love for each other.
				Learning of Saruman's betrayal from Gandalf and now realizing that they are facing threats from both Sauron and Saruman, Arwen's father, Lord Elrond, decides 				against keeping the Ring in Rivendell. He holds a council of Elves, Men, and Dwarves, also attended by Frodo and Gandalf, that decides the Ring must be destroyed in 			the fires of Mount Doom. Frodo volunteers to take the Ring, accompanied by Gandalf, Sam, Merry, Pippin, Elf Legolas, Dwarf Gimli, Boromir of Gondor, and Strider—who 			is actually Aragorn, Isildur's heir and the rightful King of Gondor. Bilbo, now living in Rivendell, gives Frodo his sword Sting, and a chainmail shirt made of 			mithril.
				The Fellowship of the Ring makes for the Gap of Rohan, but discover it is being watched by Saruman's spies. They instead set off over the mountain pass of 				Caradhras, but Saruman summons a storm that forces them to travel through the Mines of Moria, where a tentacled water beast blocks off the entrance with the 				Fellowship inside, giving them no choice but to journey to the exit on the other end. After finding the Dwarves of Moria dead, the Fellowship is attacked by Orcs 			and a cave troll. They hold them off but are confronted by Durin's Bane: a Balrog residing within the mines. While the others escape, Gandalf fends off the Balrog 			and casts it into a vast chasm, but the Balrog drags Gandalf down into the darkness with him. The devastated Fellowship reaches Lothlórien, ruled by the Elf-queen 			Galadriel, who privately informs Frodo that only he can complete the quest and that one of the Fellowship will try to take the Ring. She also shows him a vision of 			the future in which Sauron succeeds in enslaving Middle-earth, including the Shire. Meanwhile, Saruman creates an army of Uruk-hai in Isengard to find and kill the 			Fellowship.
				The Fellowship travels by river to Parth Galen. Frodo wanders off and is confronted by Boromir, who, as Lady Galadriel had warned, tries to take the Ring. Uruk-hai 			scouts then ambush the Fellowship, attempting to abduct the Hobbits. Boromir breaks free of the Ring's magic and protects Merry and Pippin, but the Uruk-Hai leader, 			Lurtz, mortally wounds Boromir as they abduct the Hobbits. Aragorn arrives and kills Lurtz before comforting Boromir as he dies, promising to help the people of 			Gondor in the coming conflict. Fearing the Ring will corrupt his friends, Frodo decides to travel to Mordor alone, but allows Sam to come along, recalling his 				promise to Gandalf to look after him. As Aragorn, Legolas, and Gimli set out to rescue Merry and Pippin, Frodo and Sam make their way down the mountain pass of Emyn 			Muil, journeying on to Mordor.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="New Line Cinema"/>
				<company name="WingNut Films"/>
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>93000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="New Zealand">
					<cities>Matamata, Wellington Region, Queenstown</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Peter Jackson</name>
				<biography>	
					Sir Peter Robert Jackson ONZ KNZM (born 31 October 1961) is a New Zealand film director, screenwriter and producer. He is best known as the director, writer and producer of the Lord of the Rings trilogy (2001–2003) and the Hobbit trilogy (2012–2014), both of which are adapted from the novels of the same name by J. R. R. Tolkien. Other notable films include the critically lauded drama Heavenly Creatures (1994), the horror comedy 					The Frighteners (1996), the epic monster remake film King Kong (2005), the World War I documentary film They Shall Not Grow Old (2018) and the 						documentary The Beatles: Get Back (2021). He is the fourth-highest-grossing film director of all-time, his films having made over $6.5 billion 						worldwide.
					Jackson began his career with the "splatstick" horror comedy Bad Taste (1987) and the black comedy Meet the Feebles (1989) before filming the zombie comedy Braindead (1992). He shared a nomination for Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay with his partner Fran Walsh for Heavenly Creatures, which brought him to mainstream prominence in the film industry. Jackson has been awarded three Academy Awards for The Lord of the Rings: 					The Return of the King (2003), including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Adapted Screenplay, His other awards include three BAFTAs, a Golden 					Globe, two Primetime Emmy Awards and four Saturn Awards among others.
					His production company is WingNut Films, and his most regular collaborators are co-writers and producers Walsh and Philippa Boyens. Jackson was made a Companion of the New Zealand Order of Merit in 2002. He was later knighted (as a Knight Companion of the order) by Sir Anand Satyanand, theGovernor-General of New Zealand, at a ceremony in Wellington in April 2010. In December 2014, Jackson was awarded a star on the Hollywood Walk of 					Fame.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Fran Walsh</name>
				<biography>	
					Dame Frances Rosemary Walsh DNZM (born 10 January 1959) is a New Zealand screenwriter and film producer.
					The partner of filmmaker Peter Jackson, Walsh has contributed to all of their films since 1989: as co-writer since Meet the Feebles, and as producer since The Lord of the Rings Trilogy. She has won three Academy Awards for the final film of the trilogy, The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Philippa Boyens</name>
				<biography>	
					Born in 1962, Boyens is the daughter of John Fraser Boyens and Jane Moana Menhennet. She was educated at Massey High School, and was later a part-time student at the University of Auckland, graduating with a BA in English and history in 1994. After that Boyens joined a theatre company and her wages were paid by the government in a PEP scheme. Boyens received a Distinguished Alumni Award from the University and Auckland in 2006. Boyens co-wrote the screenplay for Peter Jackson's films The Lord of the Rings series, King Kong, The Lovely Bones, and the three-part film The Hobbit, all with Jackson and Fran Walsh. Boyens, Jackson, and Walsh won the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay for The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King at the 76th Academy Awards in 2004. She was co-producer on every one of Jackson's films since King Kong, and on District 9. Prior to screen-writing, Boyens worked in theater as a playwright, teacher, producer, and editor. Boyens was director of the New Zealand Writers Guild for a time.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Barrie M. Osborne</name>
				<biography>	
					The son of Hertha Schwarz and William Osborne, Barrie was born in New York City and grew up in New Rochelle, New York where he graduated New Rochelle High School. He is an alumnus of Carleton College in Northfield, Minnesota and currently lives in Wellington, New Zealand. He was appointed an Officer of the New Zealand Order of Merit (ONZM), for services to the film industry, in the 2017 New Year Honours. Osborne's most notable work is The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King for which he, Peter Jackson, and Fran Walsh received the Academy Award for Best Picture. He also produced the 2013 The Great Gatsby remake, starring Leonardo DiCaprio. In 2014, Osborne, Alan B. Curtiss, and Mexican entrepreneur Max Appedole, released Gloria, a biopic of controversial Mexican pop star Gloria Trevi, directed by Christian Keller. Osborne is also preparing a possible movie trilogy about the Viking king Harald Hardrada.
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Peter Jackson</name>
				<biography>Sir Peter Robert Jackson ONZ KNZM (born 31 October 1961) is a New Zealand film director, screenwriter and producer. He is best known as the director, writer and producer of the Lord of the Rings trilogy (2001–2003) and the Hobbit trilogy (2012–2014), both of which are adapted from the novels of the same name by J. R. R. Tolkien. Other notable films include the critically lauded drama Heavenly Creatures (1994), the horror comedy The Frighteners (1996), the epic monster remake film King Kong (2005), the World War I documentary film They Shall Not Grow Old (2018) and the documentary The Beatles: Get Back (2021). He is the fourth-highest-grossing film director of all-time, his films having made over $6.5 billion worldwide Jackson began his career with the "splatstick" horror comedy Bad Taste (1987) and the black comedy Meet the Feebles (1989) before filming the zombie comedy Braindead (1992). He shared a nomination for Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay with his partner Fran Walsh for Heavenly 	Creatures, which brought him to mainstream prominence in the film industry. Jackson has been awarded three Academy Awards for The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King (2003), including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Adapted Screenplay, His other awards include three BAFTAs, a Golden Globe, two Primetime Emmy Awards and four Saturn Awards among others.
					His production company is WingNut Films, and his most regular collaborators are co-writers and producers Walsh and Philippa Boyens. Jackson was made a Companion of the New Zealand Order of Merit in 2002. He was later knighted (as a Knight Companion of the order) by Sir Anand Satyanand, the Governor-General of New Zealand, at a ceremony in Wellington in April 2010. In December 2014, Jackson was awarded a star on the Hollywood Walk of 					Fame.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Howard Shore</name>
				<biography>	
					Howard Leslie Shore OC (born October 18, 1946) is a Canadian composer, conductor and orchestrator noted for his film scores. He has composed the scores for over 80 films, most notably the scores for The Lord of the Rings and The Hobbit film trilogies. He won three Academy Awards for his work on The Lord of the Rings, with one being for the song "Into the West", an award he shared with Eurythmics lead vocalist Annie Lennox and writer/producer Fran Walsh, who wrote the lyrics. He is a consistent collaborator with director David Cronenberg, having scored all but one of his films since 1979, and collaborated with Martin Scorsese on six of his films. Shore has also composed a few concert works including one opera, The Fly, based on the plot of Cronenberg's 1986 film, which premiered at the Théâtre du Châtelet in Paris on July 2, 2008; a short piece named Fanfare for the Wanamaker Organ and the Philadelphia Orchestra; and a short overture for the Swiss 21st Century Symphony Orchestra. Shore has also composed for television, including serving as the original musical director for the American sketch comedy show Saturday Night Live from 1975 to 1980. In addition to his three Academy Awards, Shore has also won three Golden Globe Awards and four Grammy Awards.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Elijah Wood</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Frodo Baggings</character>
					<character_description>Frodo Baggins is a fictional character in J. R. R. Tolkien's writings, and one of the protagonists in The Lord of the Rings. Frodo is a hobbit of the Shire who inherits the One Ring from his cousin Bilbo Baggins, described familiarly as "uncle", and undertakes the quest to destroy it in the fires of Mount Doom in Mordor. He is mentioned in Tolkien's posthumously published works, The Silmarillion and Unfinished Tales.Frodo is repeatedly wounded during the quest, and becomes increasingly burdened by the Ring as it nears Mordor. He changes, too, growing in understanding and compassion, and avoiding violence. On his return to the Shire, he is unable to settle back into ordinary life; two years after the Ring's destruction, he is allowed to take ship to the earthly paradise of Valinor.Frodo's name comes from the Old English name Fróda, meaning "wise by experience". Commentators have written that he combines courage, selflessness, and fidelity, and that as a good[1] character, he seems unexciting but grows through his quest, an unheroic person who reaches heroic stature.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian McKellen</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Gandalf</character>
					<character_description>As a wizard and the bearer of one of the Three Rings, Gandalf has great power, but works mostly by encouraging and persuading. He sets out as Gandalf the Grey, possessing great knowledge and travelling continually. Gandalf is focused on the mission to counter the Dark Lord Sauron by destroying the One Ring. He is associated with fire; his ring of power is Narya, the Ring of Fire. As such, he delights in fireworks to entertain the hobbits of the Shire, while in great need he uses fire as a weapon. As one of the Maiar, he is an immortal spirit from Valinor, but his physical body can be killed.In The Hobbit, Gandalf assists the 13 dwarves and the hobbit Bilbo Baggins with their quest to retake the Lonely Mountain from Smaug the dragon, but leaves them to urge the White Council to expel Sauron from his fortress of Dol Guldur. In the course of the quest, Bilbo finds a magical ring. The expulsion succeeds, but in The Lord of the Rings, Gandalf reveals that Sauron's retreat was only a feint, as he soon reappeared in Mordor. Gandalf further explains that, after years of investigation, he is sure that Bilbo's ring is the One Ring that Sauron needs to dominate the whole of Middle-earth. The Council of Elrond creates the Fellowship of the Ring, with Gandalf as its leader, to defeat Sauron by destroying the Ring. He takes them south through the Misty Mountains, but is killed fighting a Balrog, an evil spirit-being, in the underground realm of Moria. After he dies, he is sent back to Middle-earth to complete his mission as Gandalf the White. He reappears to three of the Fellowship and helps to counter the enemy in Rohan, then in Gondor, and finally at the Black Gate of Mordor, in each case largely by offering guidance. When victory is complete, he crowns Aragorn as King before leaving Middle-earth for ever to return to Valinor.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Dominic Monaghan</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character></character>
					<character_description> </character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Dominic Monaghan</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Meriadoc Brandybuck</character>
					<character_description>Meriadoc Brandybuck romane J. R. R. Tolkieni The Lord of the Rings de yew karaktero. Meriadoc Brandybuck, hem yew hobbito hem zi embaze wayire iştanan Frodo Bagginso. Dewre Hireyıne de, Shire de ameyo riye dınya. Dewre Çeharıne de merdo.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>John Gilbert</name>
				<biography>John Gilbert is a film editor who works primarily in New Zealand. Gilbert has edited 17 feature films as well as television shows and short films. He won the Academy Award for Best Film Editing and the BAFTA Award for Best Editing, among several honors, for Mel Gibson's war drama Hacksaw Ridge (2016). Gilbert had earlier received various accolades for his work on Peter Jackson's The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring (2001), including the Satellite Award for Best Editing and nominations for an Academy Award, a BAFTA Award and an ACE Eddie Award.John Gilbert's first position in film was with Government filmmaking body The National Film Unit, in his native New Zealand. Gilbert was taking a break from history and anthropology studies at the time, but never returned to university, moving on to Television New Zealand, where he worked as an assistant editor and editor. Gilbert also spent time freelancing as a sound editor.Gilbert's first credit as an editor on a full-length feature was for the film Crush (1992), which was invited to the Cannes Film Festival. Gilbert received a "Best Editing" award from the New Zealand Film and Television Awards for comedy drama film Via Satellite (1998). He received a New Zealand Screen Award for editing The World's Fastest Indian (2005) and reunited with Mel Gibson on the historical drama The Professor and the Madman.Gilbert has been elected to membership in the American Cinema Editors.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Michael Semanick</name>
				<biography>Michael Semanick (born 1963) is an American sound engineer, credited as a sound re-recording mixer. He has won two Academy Awards for Best Sound and has been nominated for nine more in the same category. He has worked on more than 110 films since 1987.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Dennis Davidson" />
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="New Line Cinema" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>5.0</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>8.8</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>83</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>898200000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-5" title="John Wick" release_date="2014-10-24" duration="101" rating="PG-13">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Action" />
			<genre type="Thriller" />
		</genres>
		<plot>
				In New York City, John Wick is grieving the death of his wife Helen, who had arranged for him to receive a beagle puppy to help cope with his loss. A few days later, a group of Russian gangsters, led by Iosef Tarasov, accost John at a gas station and fail to intimidate him into selling them his 1969 Boss 429 Mustang. That night, they break into John's home, assault him, kill the puppy, and steal the car. Iosef takes the Mustang to a chop shop to remove its identifying details, but the shop owner, Aurelio, recognizes it and refuses service. Aurelio informs John that Iosef is the son of Viggo Tarasov, the boss of New York City's Russian mafia.
				Upon learning of his son's actions, Viggo berates Iosef for incurring John's wrath. He reveals John was once a hitman in his employ, and was renowned and feared in the criminal underworld as the Baba Yaga, a ruthless, relentless "man of focus, commitment, and sheer will". After John fell in love with Helen, a civilian, Viggo gave him a seemingly impossible task to earn his freedom; he succeeded.
				John recovers a concealed stash from his former career that includes weapons and gold coins. He refuses Viggo's attempt to make amends for his son's actions and kills the hit squad subsequently sent to his home. Viggo puts a $2 million bounty on John and enlists his former mentor, Marcus, to kill him. John lodges at the Continental, a luxurious hotel that serves as neutral ground for the underworld and where conducting criminal business is forbidden. Winston, the hotel's owner and John's old friend, informs him that Iosef is at a nightclub called Red Circle. John infiltrates Red Circle and confronts Iosef, but he is attacked by Viggo's henchman Kirill and forced to retreat to the Continental for medical attention.
				As John rests, a hitwoman, Ms. Perkins, sneaks into his room. Marcus sees Perkins from an adjacent building and fires a warning shot to alert John, who wakes up and subdues her. Perkins reveals Viggo has doubled the bounty for her to kill John in the hotel and has concealed a high-value stash in a church. John hires another hitman, Harry, to secure Perkins but she kills Harry and escapes.
				At the church, John destroys Viggo's cache of cash and extensive blackmail material. When Viggo arrives to assess the damage, John assaults him and his men but is hit by Kirill's car and captured. John tells Viggo he will not stop until Iosef is dead because the puppy gave him hope and a chance to not be alone in his grief for Helen. Marcus again intervenes to save John, who kills Kirill and threatens Viggo into revealing Iosef's location in a safehouse. John assaults the safehouse and kills Iosef. Marcus encourages John to return to his everyday life. Perkins witnesses this and reveals Marcus's duplicity to Viggo, who has him tortured and killed. Viggo calls John to taunt him with the details, drawing him back to the city.
				Winston has Perkins executed for breaking the Continental's rules, then informs John that Viggo is preparing to leave the city by helicopter. John races to New York Harbor, where he fights and mortally wounds Viggo. John, resigned to dying from his injuries, watches on his phone a video of Helen telling him they need to go home. He breaks into a nearby animal clinic, treats his wounds, and adopts a pit bull puppy scheduled to be euthanized before beginning to walk home.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Thunder Road Pictures" />
				<company name="87Eleven Productions" />
				<company name="MJW Films" />
				<company name="DefyNite Films" />
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>30000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United States of America">
					<cities>New York</cities>
				</country>
				<country name="Canada">
					<cities>Montreal</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Chad Stahelski</name>
				<biography>	
					Chad Stahelski (born September 20, 1968) is an American stuntman and film director. He directed the 2014 film John Wick and its three sequels. He has worked as a stuntman, stunt coordinator and second unit director on several films.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-11" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Derek Kolstad</name>
				<biography>	
					Derek Kolstad (born April 4, 1974) is an American screenwriter and film producer. He is the creator of the John Wick franchise, which began in 2014. He continued to write for the first two sequels of the franchise and is mainly known as a screenwriter of action films and shows. Originally from Madison, Wisconsin, Kolstad attended Edgewood High School of the Sacred Heart and later studied business administration at Taylor University in Indiana. He moved to California at age 24 to pursue screenwriting. He says he started writing films when he was a teenager, but he struggled to find success in Hollywood at first.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-11" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Basil Iwanyk</name>
				<biography>	
					Basil William Iwanyk (born January 4, 1970) is an American film producer. He is the founder of Thunder Road Films and most known for Sicario, The Town, Greenland and the John Wick franchise. His films have earned more than $2 billion internationally as of 2018. He is of Ukrainian descent.After starting out working for Warner Bros in the 1990s, Basil founded his own company, Thunder Road, in 2000. The company has a stellar reputation within the industry and a remarkable track record of critical and commercial success.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-11" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Leitch</name>
				<biography>
					David Leitch (born November 16, 1975) is an American filmmaker, actor, stunt performer and stunt coordinator who made his directorial debut on the 2014 action film John Wick with Chad Stahelski, though only Stahelski was credited. Leitch then directed the 2017 thriller film Atomic Blonde, starring Charlize Theron, and 2018's Deadpool 2, the sequel to the 2016 film. In 2019, he directed Hobbs and Shaw, a spin-off of the Fast and Furious franchise, and in 2022 directed Bullet Train, starring Brad Pitt.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>			
				</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Tyler Bates</name>
				<biography>	
					Tyler Bates (born June 5, 1965 is an American musician,producer, and composer for film, television, and video game scores.Much of his work is in the action and horror film genres, with films like Dawn of the Dead, 300, Sucker Punch, Halloween I and II, and the John Wick franchise. He has collaborated with directors like Zack Snyder, Rob Zombie, Neil Marshall, William Friedkin, Scott Derrickson, James Gunn, Chad Stahelski and David Leitch. In addition, he is also the former lead guitarist of the American rock band Marilyn Manson, and produced its albums The Pale Emperor and Heaven Upside Down. He's currently Jerry Cantrell‘s touring/studio member.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-11" />
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Keanu Reeves</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<other_works ID="ID-11" />
					<character>John Wick</character>
					<character_description>John Wick is a fictional character created by American screenwriter Derek Kolstad and portrayed by Canadian actor Keanu Reeves. He is the titular protagonist of the American media franchise John Wick. In the franchise's film series, he is introduced as a legendary Belarusian-American ex-hitman who left the criminal underworld after falling in love with and marrying a woman named Helen. While suffering from a terminal illness, Helen made arrangements for a puppy to be delivered to John in order to serve as his companion after her death. Days after her funeral, a Russian-American mobster — the son of John's former mafia boss — takes an interest in John's car after seeing it a gas station and is angered when John refuses to sell it to him. That night, he leads a group and breaks into John's house, assaulting him and killing his puppy before stealing his car. The attack sets John on a path of revenge, returning him to the violent lifestyle that he had left behind and eventually bringing him into conflict with the international organization of assassins of which he was once a part.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Michael Nyqvist</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Viggo Tarasov</character>
					<character_description>Viggo Tarasov inherited the leadership of the Tarasov Mob after his father died. It is mentioned that he always had a rivalry with another 'gang.' While Viggo was in a bar, he saw John Wick kill three people with a pencil. This sparked the light in Viggo's eyes; he saw John's potential and hired him to be part of the mob. Later, John asked to leave so he could marry Helen. Unwilling to let his best and most capable henchman leave his service, Viggo gave him an 'impossible task', implied to eliminate notable members of rival mobs. However, with the help of Italian crime lord Santino D'Antonio, John succeeded and Viggo had no choice but to let him retire. The assassin's "impossible task" enabled the Tarasov Mob to rise to power in New York.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Alfie Allen</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Iosef Tarasov</character>
					<character_description>Iosef was the only known child of the Russian crime lord Viggo Tarasov, and was involved with his father's crime organization. At some point, he got involved in a fiasco in Atlantic City.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian McShane</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<other_works ID="ID-6 ID-11" />
					<character>Winston</character>
					<character_description>Winston Scott is the current owner and manager of the New York Continental Hotel, an establishment that functions as a neutral territory and safe zone for criminals and hired killers. No business is allowed to be conducted on Continental grounds, and those who violate this important rule are given severe penalties: which are often ordered and overseen by Winston himself. Although he is a close friend and ally of John Wick, he is still a high-ranking and powerful member of the Continental, and does what he has to do to those who break its rules.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Lance Reddick</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Charon</character>
					<character_description>Charon was the concierge of the Continental Hotel in New York City, employed by Winston Scott as his right-hand man. Charon often interacted with John Wick in his position as the concierge of the hotel, offering John various services, such as taking care of his dog. As concierge of the New York Continental, Charon is both the face of the hotel and the guard at its gates.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Elisabet Ronaldsdottir</name>
				<biography>Elísabet Ronaldsdóttir has been working as a film editor since the late 1990s. She often works with directors Baltasar Kormákur and David Leitch. In 2008, 2012 and 2013 she was awarded the Icelandic film award Edda for best editing. Her work includes more than 45 productions. In 2018 she was appointed to the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, which awards the Oscars annually.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Evan J. Haley</name>
				<biography>Evan J Haley received his first taste with audio in 2003 while attending a concert at a local venue. The band was popular, but unsigned, and seemed to need some assistance. You can say that's when his future career in audio took flight. From that day on, Captive8 entrusted him with duties of loading in, loading out, setup, tear-down, trouble shooting all problems, personal musician technician, P.A. equipment setup, microphone placement, and running sound for F.O.H, and Monitor land. Evan always had a good ear, and was able to distinguish what sounded evenly mixed. The band was always very happy, and impressed with his work. Live sound felt as if it was second nature for Evan and he decided to apply for an intern position at the same venue he watched Captive8 perform. Evan worked at the venue every weekend for the next year learning as much as he possibly could about sound. While he worked at the club, Evan had the opportunity to run Monitor Land for all the local, and national acts that performed. While interning at the club he enrolled for school to future his education in all aspects of audio. Evan often found myself in the Pro Tools mixing and recording labs learning as much as he could about multitrack recorders, hardware and software DAW's. He continued to explore the realm of software DAW's discovering how addicting it was to record and mix sessions in Pro Tools. As his eagerness for audio continued, Evan switch his focus from music to motion picture. He set his focus to work with film as a Sound Editor/Sound Designer, and Mixer. Evan live's in Los Angeles, CA living out his dream working on a variety of different projects always striving, and pushing himself to get to the next step in his career.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Peter J. Silbermann" />
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Summit Entertainment" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.4</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>94</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>86000000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
		<franchise>
			<sequels ID="ID-11"/>
		</franchise>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-6" title="Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl" release_date="2003-06-28" duration="143" rating="PG-13">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Adventure" />
			<genre type="Fantasy" />
		</genres>
		<plot>
				In 1720, Governor Weatherby Swann and his daughter, Elizabeth, sail aboard the HMS Dauntless. Lieutenant Norrington's crew recovers a shipwrecked survivor, Will Turner. Elizabeth takes a gold medallion from around Will's neck before seeing a ship with black sails. Eight years later in Port Royal, Jamaica, Norrington is promoted to commodore and proposes to Elizabeth at Fort Charles. Elizabeth's corset makes her faint and fall into the water below, causing the medallion to emit a pulse. Captain Jack Sparrow, who initially arrived to "commandeer" a ship, rescues Elizabeth before escaping Commodore Norrington, who identifies Jack with his pirate brand. Will, now a blacksmith, meets Jack and fights long enough for Sparrow to be imprisoned.
				That night, Port Royal is attacked by the Black Pearl, the ship Elizabeth Swann saw years earlier, searching for the medallion. Invoking parley, Elizabeth is taken aboard to meet Captain Barbossa. Although she gave her name as "Elizabeth Turner" to conceal her identity as the governor's daughter, Barbossa takes Elizabeth with them. Barbossa explains that the medallion is one of 882 Aztec gold pieces in a stone chest used to bribe Cortés to stop his slaughter, but because of Cortés's greed, the heathen gods placed a curse on the gold. Barbossa's crew found the treasure at Isla de Muerta, but after spending it, they feel and taste nothing, and turn into immortal undead skeletons in the moonlight. To lift the curse, Barbossa's crew must return all the gold with their blood. Having discovered that "Bootstrap Bill" Turner sent a piece to his child, Barbossa sent Bootstrap to the bottom of the ocean. Assuming Elizabeth is Bootstrap's child, Barbossa intends to use her blood instead.
				To save Elizabeth, Will frees Jack, who learns that Turner is the son of Bootstrap Bill. They distract Norrington with a staged attempt to steal the Dauntless, allowing them to commandeer the HMS Interceptor, then head to Tortuga to find Joshamee Gibbs and recruit a crew. Will learns from Gibbs that Sparrow was captain of the Black Pearl before Barbossa organized a mutiny and marooned him on an island. Arriving at Isla de Muerta, Jack and Will sneak into the treasure grotto, where Barbossa fails to lift the curse with Elizabeth's "Turner" blood. Will and Elizabeth escape with the medallion on the Interceptor, while Sparrow is captured by Barbossa and locked in the brig aboard the Pearl. A battle ensues between the Pearl and the Interceptor, with the crew captured and the ship destroyed. Having realized it is his blood Barbossa needs, Will surrenders himself to ensure Elizabeth's freedom. Barbossa agrees but maroons Jack and Elizabeth. The next morning, Elizabeth makes a smoke signal, then Jack and Elizabeth are rescued aboard the Dauntless. Elizabeth accepts Norrington's marriage proposal on the condition to rescue Will from Barbossa.
				That night, Jack and Norrington make a plan to ambush the pirates at Isla de Muerta, but Norrington plans to ambush the pirates himself and Sparrow convinces Barbossa to not lift the curse until after they've killed Norrington's men. Having anticipated the battle to come, Jack secretly palms a coin for himself to become immortal, then frees Will and duels Barbossa in the cave. As Norrington's crew battle skeletons aboard the Dauntless, Elizabeth sneaks off to free Jack's crew, who flee on the Pearl, leaving Swann to save Will and Jack by herself. After Elizabeth helps defeat some of Barbossa's crewmen, Sparrow shoots Barbossa just as Will returns both remaining coins with their blood into the chest, lifting the curse. Now mortal, Barbossa dies from Sparrow's gunshot, and the rest of Barbossa's crew are killed or surrendered.
				At Port Royal, Will declares his love for Elizabeth, before rescuing Jack, who was about to be hanged. After a scuffle, Jack and Will are surrounded. Elizabeth stands by their side, choosing Turner over Norrington, who stands down. Sparrow falls into the water, then is rescued by the Black Pearl and her new crew. Norrington decides to give Sparrow "one day's head start" before pursuit. Governor Swann gives his blessings to Will and Elizabeth, while Jack Sparrow is made captain of the Pearl and sails off to the horizon.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Walt Disney Pictures" />
				<company name="Jerry Bruckheimer Films" />
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>140000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="Jamaica">
					<cities>Port Royal</cities>
				</country>
				<country name="Dominican Republic"/>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Gore Verbinski</name>
				<biography>	
					Gregor Justin "Gore" Verbinski (born March 16, 1964) is an American film maker and musician. He is best known for directing The Ring and the first three Pirates of the Caribbean films, and for producing and directing the animated film Rango. For his work on Rango, Verbinski won the Academy Award for Best Animated Film, the BAFTA Award for Best Animated Film, and was nominated for the Golden Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Ted Elliott</name>
				<biography>	
					Ted Elliott (born July 4, 1961) is an American screenwriter and film producer. Along with his writing partner Terry Rossio, Elliott has written some of the most successful American films of the past 30 years, including Aladdin (1992), Shrek (2001) and the Pirates of the Caribbean series (2003-11).
					He was attached to write a feature version of Monkey Island, which never happened.
					In 2004, he was elected to the board of directors of the Writers Guild of America; his term on the board ended in 2006. In 2005, Elliott ran for president of the Writers Guild of America, west, but lost to animation writer and historical figurine maker Patric Verrone. Verrone received 1301 votes; Elliott received 591.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Jerry Bruckheimer</name>
				<biography>	
					Jerome Leon Bruckheimer (born September 21, 1943) is an American film and television producer. He has been active in the genres of action, drama, comedy, fantasy, and science fiction.
					Bruckheimer has produced films like Flashdance, Top Gun, The Rock, Crimson Tide, Con Air, Armageddon, Enemy of the State, Black Hawk Down, Pearl Harbor, Kangaroo Jack, as well as the Beverly Hills Cop, Bad Boys, Pirates of the Caribbean, and National Treasure franchises. Many of his films have been co-produced by Paramount and Disney, while many of his television series have been co-produced by Warner Bros. and CBS Studios. In July 2003, Bruckheimer was honored by Variety as the first producer in Hollywood history to produce the top two highest-grossing films of a single weekend: Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl and Bad Boys II. In 2023, Top Gun: Maverick earned him a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Picture.
					His best known television series are CSI: Crime Scene Investigation, CSI: Miami, CSI: NY, CSI: Cyber, Without a Trace, Cold Case, Lucifer, and the American version of The Amazing Race. For the lattermost, he won ten Primetime Emmy Awards. At one point, three of his TV series ranked among the top 10 in the U.S. ratings—a unique feat in television.
					Bruckheimer is also the co-founder and co-majority owner (along with David Bonderman) of the Seattle Kraken, the 2021 expansion team of the National Hockey League.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Klaus Badelt</name>
				<biography>	
					Klaus Badelt (born 12 June 1967) is a German composer, producer, and arranger of film scores. He is known for his collaborations with Hans Zimmer, helping to write scores for dozens of critically acclaimed films including The Thin Red Line, The Prince of Egypt, and Gladiator. Independently, he is known for his work on Hollywood blockbuster films such as Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl, Equilibrium, K-19: The Widowmaker, Basic, and TMNT, and for his work in French and Chinese cinema as well as a number of films by Werner Herzog.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Johnny Depp</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Jack Sparrow</character>
					<character_description>Captain Jack Sparrow is a fictional character and the main protagonist of the Pirates of the Caribbean film series and franchise. An early iteration of Sparrow was created by screenwriters Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio, but the final version of the character was created by actor Johnny Depp, who also portrayed him.[1][2][3]The characterization of Sparrow is based on a combination of The Rolling Stones' guitarist Keith Richards and Looney Tunes cartoons, specifically the characters Bugs Bunny and Pepé Le Pew. He first appears in the 2003 film Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl. He later appears in the sequels Dead Man's Chest (2006), At World's End (2007), On Stranger Tides (2011), and Dead Men Tell No Tales (2017).In the films, Sparrow is one of the nine pirate lords in the Brethren Court, the Pirate Lords of the Seven Seas. He can be treacherous and survives mostly by using wit and negotiation rather than by force, opting to flee most dangerous situations and to fight only when necessary.Sparrow is introduced seeking to regain his ship, the Black Pearl, from his mutinous first mate Hector Barbossa. After succeeding, he attempts to escape his blood debt to the legendary Davy Jones while fighting the East India Trading Company. Later, when searching for the Fountain of Youth, he is abducted and taken upon Blackbeard's Queen Anne's Revenge and is forced to lead him to the Fountain while the Black Pearl is trapped in a bottle. In a later adventure, when the ghost spanish Captain Armando Salazar comes after him, he searches for the Trident of Poseidon while also seeking to restore the Pearl to its original form.The Pirates of the Caribbean series was inspired by the Disney theme park ride of the same name, and when the ride was revamped in 2006, the character of Captain Jack Sparrow was added to it. He headlined the Legend of Captain Jack Sparrow attraction at Disney's Hollywood Studios, and is the subject of spin-off novels, including a children's book series, Pirates of the Caribbean: Jack Sparrow, which chronicles his childhood years.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian McShane</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<other_works ID="ID-5 ID-11" />
					<character>Edward Teach</character>
					<character_description>Blackbeard (d. 1718), otherwise known as Edward Teach (probably an assumed name), was an infamous English pirate who operated in the Caribbean and Atlantic during a surprisingly short career lasting just 15 months. With his long black beard tied with ribbons, lighted fuses under his hat, and bristling with pistols, Blackbeard’s name, reputation, and appearance were all calculated to freeze his victims with dreadful terror.Thanks largely to a wildly exaggerated and mostly fictional portrait by the author Charles Johnson/Daniel Defoe (1660-1731), Blackbeard became the most colourful of all the pirates of the so-called Golden Age of Piracy. He is portrayed as a man with no morals or scruples, either towards his innocent victims or his own crews, and as a pirate who got his just deserts when he was killed in action against the Royal Navy, but then only after being struck down by five pistol shots and 20 sword cuts.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Geoffrey Rush</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Hector Barbossa</character>
					<character_description>Captain Hector Barbossa is a fictional character of the Pirates of the Caribbean franchise, appearing in all five films in the series. Starting out as a villainous undead pirate in The Curse of the Black Pearl (2003), the character dies at the end of the film. However, he is revealed to have been brought back to life at the end of Dead Man's Chest before appearing in anti-heroic roles as a Pirate Lord in At World's End (2007), a privateer with the Royal Navy in On Stranger Tides (2011), and finally as the rich and influential leader of his own pirate fleet in Dead Men Tell No Tales (2017). Throughout the series, the character has been conceptualized as a "dark trickster" and the evil counterpart of Captain Jack Sparrow.[1]</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Zoe Saldana</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Anamaria</character>
					<character_description>Anamaria was a tough female smuggler and pirate who operated in the Caribbean. What little is known of her life came largely from her adventures with the infamous Captain Jack Sparrow, who once referred to Anamaria as the "delicate flower of the Caribbean." The Jolly Mon was once Anamaria's boat until it was "borrowed" by Jack Sparrow, who eventually sailed it to the town of Port Royal, where it sank to the bottom of the harbor. Anamaria later reunited with Captain Sparrow when Joshamee Gibbs brought together a ragtag group to help crew the Interceptor. Believing Jack had a debt to repay, she joined the line of sailors and accused him of stealing her boat, adding a couple of slaps for emphasis. In turn, Jack offered the Interceptor, knowing Anamaria was a good sailor and that he needed her onboard. Anamaria sailed the Interceptor to Isla de Muerta during Will Turner's attempt to rescue Elizabeth Swann from Hector Barbossa's cursed crew, but was soon imprisoned with the other crewmen in the brig of the Black Pearl. After taking the Black Pearl, Anamaria served under Jack Sparrow's command, embarking on several misadventures before leaving the crew.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Craig Wood</name>
				<biography>Craig Wood is an Australian film editor working in America.Born in Sydney, Wood began his career at the age of 19 as an assistant editor in the Australian Broadcasting Corporation's documentary department before moving into music video and advertising work.He has worked as an editor on almost all of director Gore Verbinski’s films, including the 1996 short film The Ritual, as well as on over a dozen Verbinski-directed commercials, including the Clio Awards and Silver Lion-winning Budweiser "Frogs" (1995).</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Christopher Boyes</name>
				<biography>Christopher Boyes is an American sound engineer. He has won four Academy Awards and has been nominated for another eleven. He has worked on more than 100 films since 1991.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-3 ID-7 ID-8 ID-9" />
			</employee>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Gabriela Gutentag" />
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Buena Vista Pictures Distribution" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4.8</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>8.1</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>86</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>654300000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-7" title="Twilight" release_date="2008-11-17" duration="121" rating="PG-13">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Fantasy" />
			<genre type="Romance" />
		</genres>	
		<plot>
				Twilight is a 2008 American romantic fantasy vampire film directed by Catherine Hardwicke from a screenplay by Melissa Rosenberg, based on the 2005 novel of the same name by Stephenie Meyer. It is the first installment in The Twilight Saga film series. The film stars Kristen Stewart and Robert Pattinson as Bella Swan, a teenage girl, and Edward Cullen, a vampire, and focuses on the development of Bella and Edward's relationship and the subsequent efforts of Edward and his family to keep Bella safe from another coven of vampires.
				The project was in development for approximately three years at Paramount Pictures' MTV Films, during which time a film adaptation that differed significantly from the novel was written. Summit Entertainment acquired the rights to the novel after the project's stagnant development. Melissa Rosenberg wrote a new adaptation of the novel shortly before the 2007–2008 Writers Guild of America strike and sought to be faithful to the novel's storyline. Principal photography began in March 2008 and took 44 days, being completed on May 2; the film was shot in the states of Oregon and Washington.
				Twilight premiered in Los Angeles on November 17, 2008,(citation needed) and was theatrically released in the United States on November 21, by Summit Entertainment. Despite receiving mixed reviews from critics, the film grossed over $407 million worldwide. It was released on DVD and Blu-ray Disc on March 21, 2009, and became the most purchased DVD of the year. The soundtrack was released on November 4, 2008.
				The film was followed by four sequels: New Moon (2009), Eclipse (2010), Breaking Dawn – Part 1 (2011), and Breaking Dawn – Part 2 (2012)
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Temple Hill Entertainment" />
				<company name="Maverick Films" />
				<company name="Goldcrest Film Finance" />
				<company name="Aura Films" />
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>37000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United States of America">
					<cities>Oregon, Washington</cities>
				</country>
				<country name="Canada">
					<cities>British Columbia</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Catherine Hardwicke</name>
				<biography>	
					Helen Catherine Hardwicke (born October 21, 1955) is an American film director, production designer, and screenwriter. Her directorial work includes Thirteen (2003), which she co-wrote with Nikki Reed, the film's co-star, Lords of Dogtown (2005), The Nativity Story (2006), Twilight (2008), Red Riding Hood (2011), Plush (2013), Miss You Already (2015), Miss Bala (2019), and Prisoner's Daughter (2022).
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Melissa Rosenberg</name>
				<biography>	
					Melissa Anne Rosenberg is an American television writer, television producer, and screenwriter. She has worked in both film and television and has won a Peabody Award. She has also been nominated for two Emmy Awards, and two Writers Guild of America Awards. Since joining the Writers Guild of America, she has been involved in its board of directors and was a strike captain during the 2007–2008 Writers Guild of America strike. She supports female screenwriters through the WGA Diversity Committee and co-founded the League of Hollywood Women Writers.She worked on several television series between 1993 and 2003 before joining The O.C.'s writing staff, eventually leaving the show to write the 2006 film Step Up. From 2006 to 2009, she served as the head writer of the Showtime series Dexter, rising to executive producer by the time she departed at the end of the fourth season. She wrote her second produced screenplay, the 2008 film adaptation of Stephenie Meyer's novel Twilight in 2007, and then adapted the novel's three sequels.Rosenberg is also widely known as the creator of the Netflix series Jessica Jones.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Mark Morgan</name>
				<biography>
					Mark Paul Morgan is an American film producer. He has been a producer and executive producer on films including The Twilight Saga film series, Percy Jackson and the Olympians: The Lightning Thief, and the Agent Cody Banks films.	
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Carter Burwell</name>
				<biography>	
					Carter Benedict Burwell (born November 18, 1954) is an American film composer. He has consistently collaborated with the Coen brothers, having scored most of their films. Burwell has also scored other films by other directors such as Bill Condon, Todd Haynes, Spike Jonze, Martin McDonagh, James Foley, Brian Helgeland, and John Lee Hancock. He has received Academy Awards nominations for Best Original Score for Haynes's Carol (2015) and McDonagh's films Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri (2017) and The Banshees Of Inisherin (2022).
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Kristen Stewart</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Bella Swan</character>
					<character_description>Isabella Marie Cullen is the protagonist character of the Twilight book series by Stephenie Meyer. She is initially an ordinary teenage girl, but during the series, Bella marries vampire Edward Cullen, with whom she has a human-vampire hybrid daughter, Renesmee Cullen. The Twilight series, consisting of the novels Twilight, New Moon, Eclipse, and Breaking Dawn, is primarily narrated from Bella's point of view. In The Twilight Saga film series, Bella is portrayed by actress Kristen Stewart.She is the daughter of Charlie Swan and Renée Swan-Dwyer and the daughter-in-law of Edward Masen Sr. and Elizabeth Masen (Edward's deceased biological parents). Bella is the step-daughter of Phil Dwyer (Renée's second husband) and the adoptive daughter-in-law of Esme Cullen and Carlisle Cullen (Edward's second and adoptive parents). Bella is the adoptive sister-in-law of Alice Cullen and Emmett Cullen as well as Rosalie Hale and Jasper Hale, the granddaughter of Geoffrey and Helen Swan (Charlie's deceased parents) and Marie Higginbotham (Renée's deceased mother).In Twilight, 17-year-old Bella moves to her father's home in Forks, Washington, meets the mysterious Cullen family, and falls in love with seemingly teenage Edward Cullen. However, she soon discovers that the family is a coven of vampires. Bella expresses a desire to become a vampire herself, but Edward refuses to turn her. In the second novel, New Moon, Edward and the other Cullens leave Forks in an effort to keep now-18-year-old human Bella safe from the vampire world. Jacob Black, a member of the Quileute tribe who is also a shape-shifter taking a werewolf form, comforts the distraught and severely depressed Bella. She comes to care deeply for Jacob, though less than she loves Edward. At the end of Eclipse, she becomes engaged to Edward Cullen, and they marry in Breaking Dawn, one month prior to her 19th birthday. On their honeymoon, she becomes pregnant, and, due to the peculiar nature of her baby, Bella nearly dies giving birth to their daughter, Renesmee. Edward turns Bella into a vampire to save her.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Robert Pattinson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Edward Cullen</character>
					<character_description>Edward Cullen (né Edward Anthony Masen, Jr.) is a character in the Twilight book series by Stephenie Meyer. He is featured in the novels Twilight, New Moon, Eclipse and Breaking Dawn, and their corresponding film adaptations, and the novel Midnight Sun—a re-telling of the events of Twilight from Edward's perspective. Edward is a telepathic vampire who, over the course of the series, falls in love with, marries, and fathers a child with Bella Swan, a human teenager who later chooses to become a vampire as well. In the films, Edward is played by actor Robert Pattinson.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Taylor Lautner</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Jacob Black</character>
					<character_description>Jacob Black is a character in the Twilight book series by Stephenie Meyer. He is described as an attractive Native American of the Quileute tribe in La Push, near Forks, Washington. In the second book of the series, New Moon, he discovers that he is a therianthrope who can shapeshift into a wolf. For the majority of the series, Jacob competes with Edward Cullen for Bella Swan's love. In The Twilight Saga film series, Jacob is played by Taylor Lautner.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Peter Facinelli</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Dr. Carlisle Cullen</character>
					<character_description>Carlisle Cullen (pronounced Car-lyle) was born in 1640 in London, England and is the founder and leader of the Olympic coven. He is the second husband of Esme Cullen and the adoptive father of Emmett, Alice, Edward Cullen, and Jasper and Rosalie Hale. He is also the adoptive father-in-law of Bella Swan and adoptive grandfather of Renesmee Cullen.In his human life, Carlisle was very compassionate, when he was turned this manifested into unparalleled compassion that allowed him to perfect his lifestyle as a "vegetarian" among vampires, to the point that he is able to completely resist the temptation of human blood even if it is in large amounts and pass this restraint to his family. His Life and Death counterpart is Carine Cullen.He is portrayed by Peter Facinelli in the movie adaptations. He is also portrayed by James Physick and Justin Rose in two separate segments.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Nancy Richardson</name>
				<biography>Nancy Richardson's credits include Stand and Deliver, To Sleep with Anger, Selena, Thirteen, Lords of Dogtown, Twilight, Step Up, and Fighting with my Family. She has served as a Creative Advisor for the Sundance Directors Lab several times. She has also been a professor at UCLA's Department of Film, Television and Digital Media for 20 years.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Christopher Boyes</name>
				<biography>Christopher Boyes is an American sound engineer. He has won four Academy Awards and has been nominated for another eleven. He has worked on more than 100 films since 1991.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-3 ID-6 ID-8 ID-9" />
			</employee>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Summit Entertainment" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>3</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>5.3</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>49</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>408400000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-8" title="Aquaman" release_date="2018-11-26" duration="143" rating="PG">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Superhero" />
			<genre type="Fantasy"/>
		</genres>
		<plot>
				Aquaman is a 2018 American superhero film based on the DC character of the same name. Co-produced and distributed by Warner Bros. Pictures, it is the sixth film in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU). The film was directed by James Wan from a screenplay by David Leslie Johnson-McGoldrick and Will Beall. It stars Jason Momoa as Arthur Curry / Aquaman, who sets out to lead the underwater kingdom of Atlantis and stop his half-brother, King Orm, from uniting the seven underwater kingdoms to destroy the surface world. Amber Heard, Willem Dafoe, Patrick Wilson, Dolph Lundgren, Yahya Abdul-Mateen II, and Nicole Kidman appear in supporting roles.
				Development began in 2004 but did not gain traction until Man of Steel was released in 2013. In August 2014, Beall and Kurt Johnstad were hired to write competing scripts. Wan signed on as director in April 2015, and in July 2016, the film moved forward with Beall's screenplay. The main cast was confirmed through 2016 and early 2017. Principal photography began in Australia in May 2017, taking place at Village Roadshow Studios on the Gold Coast, Queensland, Australia, with additional production teams in Canada, Italy and Morocco. Filming concluded the following October. Several vendors provided visual effects, ranging from high-detail hair simulations to the creation of CGI animals and locations.
				Aquaman premiered in London on November 26, 2018, and was released in the United States on December 21. While the film received mixed reviews from critics, it grossed $1.152 billion worldwide, making it the highest-grossing DCEU film, the highest-grossing film based on a DC Comics character, the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2018, and the 20th highest-grossing film of all time. An animated miniseries set after the film, Aquaman: King of Atlantis, aired from October 14 to October 28, 2021, while a live-action sequel film, Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom, is set to be released on December 20, 2023.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Warner Bros. Pictures" />
				<company name="DC Entertainment" />
				<company name="DC Films" />
				<company name="RatPac Entertainment" />
				<company name="Cruel and Unusual Films" />
				<company name="The Safran Company" />
				<company name="Mad Ghost Productions" />
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>200000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="Australia"/>
				<country name="Italy"/>
				<country name="Canada"/>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>James Wan</name>
				<biography>	
					James Wan (born 26 February 1977) is an Australian filmmaker. He has primarily worked in the horror genre as the co-creator of the Saw and Insidious franchises and the creator of The Conjuring Universe. The lattermost is the highest-grossing horror franchise at over $2 billion. Wan is also the founder of film and television production company Atomic Monster.Beginning his career with the Saw franchise, Wan made his feature directorial debut with his first film in 2004. The franchise became commercially successful and grossed more than $1 billion globally. Following a period of setbacks, Wan found new success with the Insidious series, in which he directed the first film in 2010 and its 2013 sequel. The same year as the second Insidious, Wan directed the first Conjuring film to critical and commercial success. He served as the director of the second installment in 2016 and produced subsequent films in the franchise.Outside of horror, Wan directed Furious 7 (2015), the seventh installment of the Fast and Furious franchise, and the DC Extended Universe superhero films Aquaman (2018) and the upcoming Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom. Both Furious 7 and Aquaman grossed over $1 billion, making Wan the eighth director with two films to reach the milestone.He is the 19th highest-grossing director of all time as of 2021, with his films having grossed over $3.7 billion worldwide.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Will Beall</name>
				<biography>	
					Will Beall is an American screenwriter and former Los Angeles Police Department detective. He is best known for writing the scripts for Gangster Squad (2013) and the DC Extended Universe films Aquaman (2018) and Zack Snyder's Justice League (2021), and for developing the police TV series Training Day and Deputy, which were canceled after a single season.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Peter Safran</name>
				<biography>
					Peter Safran (born 22 November 1965) is a British-American film producer and manager. He currently serves as the co-chairperson and CEO of DC Studios alongside James Gunn.	
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Jason Momoa</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Arthur Curry</character>
					<character_description>Arthur Curry, also known by his superhero moniker Aquaman, is a fictional character in the DC Extended Universe based on the DC Comics superhero of the same name. He is portrayed by American actor Jason Momoa. Originally appearing as a cameo in Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice, Curry had a prominent role in the film Justice League and its director's cut, and is later the subject of his own film Aquaman. Momoa also cameoed in the first season finale of the HBO Max series Peacemaker and the film The Flash. The DCEU marks Aquaman's first portrayal in cinema, with his character having been re-imagined as compared to his comics counterpart.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Amber Heard</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Mera</character>
					<character_description>Mera is a superheroine appearing in American comic books published by DC Comics. Created by Jack Miller and Nick Cardy, the character first appeared in Aquaman #11 (September 1963).Originally portrayed as a supporting character to her husband, the superhero Aquaman, possessing the formidable hydrokinetic power to create and control water, modern writers have given greater emphasis to her superhuman physical strength. Mera has been depicted as a member of DC Comics' flagship superhero team, the Justice League. Queen Mera's earlier storylines have also portrayed her mental breakdown, as she was faced with crippling loss. The stories explored her attempts at coping with lasting anger and rage. More recent storylines have explored her approach to rulership in comparison to her husband.The character has been adapted substantially in various media, she was played by Elena Satine on Smallville and most notably featured in the DC Extended Universe where Amber Heard portrayed Mera in Justice League and its director's cut,reprised the role in Aquaman and will return in Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom. The character has also been adapted in the animated Young Justice television series.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Patrick Wilson</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Ocean Master</character>
					<character_description>Orm Marius, aka the Ocean Master, is the half-brother of Aquaman plotting to overthrow Aquaman, who is considered the rightful king of Atlantis. Although he is jailed for an attempt on the "surface world" and escapes, he is conflicted between his family rivalry and the safety of Atlantis, the latter being more important to him than the former.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Randall Park</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Dr. Stephen Shin</character>
					<character_description>Stephen Shin was a scientist and friend of Tom Curry. He helped a young Aquaman develop his powers, but would later grow obsessed with finding out where the lost city of Atlantis was located.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Kirk Morri</name>
				<biography>Best known for his work in the the horror thriller The Conjuring (2013) and the action movie Furious Seven (2015), Kirk Morri is an American film editor. He started out as an assistant editor in the mid-1990s, and subsequently made his independent editorial debut with the horror film Feast in 2005.</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Christopher Boyes</name>
				<biography>Boyes is an American sound engineer who has won four Academy Awards. He has worked on over 70 films since 1991.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-3 ID-6 ID-7 ID-9" />
			</employee>
			<marketing_company>
				<company name="Curt Cash" />
			</marketing_company>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Morgan Jago" />
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Warner Bros. Pictures" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>3</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>6.8</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>66</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>1149000000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-9" title="Barbie" release_date="2023-07-09" duration="114" rating="G">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Adventure" />
			<genre type="Comedy" />
			<genre type="Fantasy" />
		</genres>
		<plot>
				Barbie is a 2023 fantasy comedy film directed by Greta Gerwig from a screenplay she wrote with Noah Baumbach. Based on the eponymous fashion dolls by Mattel, it is the first live-action Barbie film after numerous computer-animated films and specials. The film stars Margot Robbie as the title character and Ryan Gosling as Ken, and follows the pair on a journey of self-discovery following an existential crisis. The supporting cast includes America Ferrera, Kate McKinnon, Issa Rae, Rhea Perlman, and Will Ferrell.
				A live-action Barbie film was announced in September 2009 by Universal Pictures with Laurence Mark producing. Development began in April 2014, when Sony Pictures acquired the film rights. Following multiple writer and director changes and the casting of Amy Schumer and later Anne Hathaway as Barbie, the rights were transferred to Warner Bros. Pictures in October 2018. Robbie was cast in 2019, after Gal Gadot turned down the role due to scheduling conflicts, and Gerwig was announced as director and co-writer with Baumbach in 2020. The rest of the cast was announced in early 2022, with principal photography occurring primarily at Warner Bros. Studios, Leavesden, in England and at the Venice Beach Skatepark in Los Angeles from March to July of that year.
				Barbie premiered at the Shrine Auditorium in Los Angeles on July 9, 2023, and was released in the United States on July 21. Its simultaneous release with Universal's Oppenheimer led to the "Barbenheimer" cultural phenomenon, which encouraged audiences to see both films as a double feature. The film received critical acclaim and has grossed $1.44 billion, becoming the highest-grossing film of 2023 as well as the highest-grossing film by a solo female director, the highest-grossing film ever released by Warner Bros., and the 14th highest-grossing film of all time.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Heyday Films" />
				<company name="LuckyChap Entertainment" />
				<company name="NB/GG Pictures" />
				<company name="Mattel Films" />
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>145000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United States of America"/>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Greta Gerwig</name>
				<biography>	
					Greta Celeste Gerwig (born August 4, 1983) is an American actress, writer, and director. Initially known for working on mumblecore films, she has since expanded from acting in and co-writing independent films to directing major studio films. Gerwig was included in the annual Time 100 list of the most influential people in the world in 2018.Gerwig began her career working with Joe Swanberg on films such as Hannah Takes the Stairs (2007) and Nights and Weekends (2008).She has collaborated with her partner Noah Baumbach on several films, including Greenberg (2010) and Frances Ha (2012), for which she received a Golden Globe Award nomination, Mistress America (2015), and White Noise (2022). She also acted in such films as Whit Stillman's Damsels in Distress (2011), Woody Allen's To Rome with Love (2012), Rebecca Miller's Maggie's Plan (2015), Pablo Larraín's Jackie (2016), Mike Mills' 20th Century Women (2016), and Wes Anderson's Isle of Dogs (2018).As a solo filmmaker, Gerwig has written and directed the coming-of-age films Lady Bird (2017) and Little Women (2019), both of which earned nominations for the Academy Award for Best Picture. For the former, she received Academy Award nominations for Best Director and Best Original Screenplay, and for the latter, she was nominated for Best Adapted Screenplay. Her next directorial, the fantasy comedy Barbie (2023), which she co-wrote with Baumbach, became the first film from a solo female director to gross over $1 billion worldwide.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Noah Baumbach</name>
				<biography>	
					Noah Baumbach (born September 3, 1969) is an American film director and screenwriter. He is known for making comedies set in New York City, and his works are inspired by writer-directors such as Woody Allen and Whit Stillman. His frequent collaborators include Wes Anderson, Adam Driver, and Greta Gerwig.Baumbach gained attention for his early films Kicking and Screaming (1995), and Mr. Jealousy (1997). His breakthrough film The Squid and the Whale (2005) earned him a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay. He started with his long time collaborations with Gerwig with Greenberg (2010), and continued with Frances Ha (2013), Mistress America (2015), White Noise (2022) and Barbie (2023).His other films include Margot at the Wedding (2007), While We're Young (2014), and The Meyerowitz Stories (2017). His film Marriage Story (2019) earned an Academy Award for Best Picture nomination and Baumbach's second Best Original Screenplay nomination. He is also known for co-writing with Anderson on The Life Aquatic with Steve Zissou (2004) and Fantastic Mr. Fox (2009).
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>David Heyman</name>
				<biography>
					David Jonathan Heyman (born 26 July 1961) is a British film producer and the founder of Heyday Films. Heyman is best known as the primary producer of all eight installments of the Harry Potter film series, which are based on a series of popular fantasy novels of the same name by author J. K. Rowling. He then produced all three installments of its spin-off prequel series, Fantastic Beasts. His work makes him the second-most commercially successful producer of all time.
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-1" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Margot Robbie</name>
				<biography>
					Margot Elise Robbie (born 2 July 1990) is an Australian actress and producer. Known for her work in both blockbuster and independent films, she has received various accolades, including nominations for two Academy Awards, five BAFTA Awards and four Golden Globe Awards. Time named her one of the 100 most influential people in the world in 2017, and Forbes named her one of the world's highest-paid actresses in 2019.Born and raised in Queensland, Robbie began her career in 2008 on the television series Neighbours, on which she was a regular until 2011. After moving to America, she led the television series Pan Am (2011–2012) and had her breakthrough in 2013 with Martin Scorsese’s black comedy film The Wolf of Wall Street. She achieved wider recognition with starring roles as Jane Porter in The Legend of Tarzan (2016) and Harley Quinn in the DC Extended Universe films, beginning with Suicide Squad (2016).Robbie received critical acclaim and a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actress for her portrayal of figure skater Tonya Harding in the biopic I, Tonya (2017). This acclaim continued for her performances as Queen Elizabeth I in Mary Queen of Scots (2018), Sharon Tate in Once Upon a Time in Hollywood (2019), and a Fox News employee in Bombshell (2019). She received BAFTA Award nominations for all three and a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for the last. Robbie has since starred as an aspiring actress in the period film Babylon (2022) and the titular fashion doll in the comedy Barbie (2023), which emerged as her highest-grossing release.Robbie and her husband, filmmaker Tom Ackerley, co-founded the production company LuckyChap Entertainment in 2014, under which they have produced several films, including I, Tonya, Promising Young Woman (2020) and Barbie, as well as the Hulu series Dollface (2019–2022) and the Netflix miniseries Maid (2021).
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Mark Ronson</name>
				<biography>
					Mark Daniel Ronson (born 4 September 1975) is a British musician, DJ, record producer, songwriter, and remixer. He is best known for his collaborations with artists such as Amy Winehouse, Lady Gaga, Dua Lipa, Adele, Lily Allen, Duran Duran, Miley Cyrus, Queens of the Stone Age, and Bruno Mars. He has received seven Grammy Awards, including Producer of the Year for Winehouse's album Back to Black (2006) and two for Record of the Year singles "Rehab" and "Uptown Funk". He received an Oscar, a Golden Globe and a Grammy Award for co-writing "Shallow" (performed by Lady Gaga and Bradley Cooper) for the film A Star Is Born (2018).Ronson was born in London and raised in New York City. His stepfather is Foreigner guitarist Mick Jones, which contributed to a childhood surrounded by music. While attending New York University, Ronson became a popular DJ in the hip-hop scene. His debut album, Here Comes the Fuzz, failed to have an effect on the charts. In 2006, he received acclaim for producing albums for Lily Allen, Christina Aguilera, and Amy Winehouse. In 2007, Ronson released his second album, Version. The album reached number two in the UK and included three top ten singles and earned him the Brit Award for British Male Solo Artist. He subsequently released his third studio album, Record Collection, which peaked at number two in the UK.In 2014, Ronson released his single "Uptown Funk" featuring vocals from Bruno Mars. The single spent 14 consecutive weeks at number one on the U.S. Billboard Hot 100 and seven non-consecutive weeks at number one on the UK Singles Chart and became one of the best-selling singles of all-time. His fourth studio album, Uptown Special, became his most successful album to date. In 2018, he founded his own label, Zelig Records (an imprint of Columbia Records), and formed the duo Silk City with fellow producer Diplo; they released their debut single "Electricity" featuring Dua Lipa for which he received the Grammy Award for Best Dance Recording.In 2015, he became a patron of the Amy Winehouse Foundation, which helps disadvantaged youth through music. He has also worked with the End the Silence campaign to raise money and awareness for the Hope and Homes for Children charity and served as an artist mentor at Turnaround Arts, a national program of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, which helped low-performing schools through arts education.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Margot Robbie</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Barbie</character>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ryan Gosling</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<other_works ID="ID-10" />
					<character>Ken</character>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Will Ferrell</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>CEO of Mattel</character>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Michael Cera </name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Allan</character>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Nick Houy</name>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Christopher Boyes</name>
				<biography>Boyes is an American sound engineer who has won four Academy Awards. He has worked on over 70 films since 1991.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-3 ID-6 ID-7 ID-8" />
			</employee>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Stu Oakley" />
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Warner Bros. Pictures" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.0</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>80</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>1441000000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-10" title="The Notebook" release_date="2004-05-20" duration="124" rating="PG">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Romance" />
			<genre type="Drama" />
		</genres>
		<plot>
				The Notebook is a 2004 American romantic drama film directed by Nick Cassavetes, from a screenplay by Jeremy Leven and Jan Sardi, and based on the 1996 novel of the same name by Nicholas Sparks. The film stars Ryan Gosling and Rachel McAdams as a young couple who fall in love in the 1940s. Their story is read from a notebook in the present day by an elderly man, telling the tale to a fellow nursing home resident.
				The Notebook had its world premiere at the Seattle International Film Festival on May 20, 2004, and was theatrically released in the United States on June 25, 2004. Despite generally mixed reviews from critics, Gosling and McAdams were singled out for praise for their performances. The film was a sleeper hit at the box office, grossing $117 million against its $29 million budget, and has become a cult classic in the years since its release. On November 11, 2012, an extended version premiered on ABC Family with deleted scenes added back into the original storyline.
				The film earned several accolades, including the MTV Movie Award for Best Kiss for Gosling and McAdams at the 2005 MTV Movie Awards. At the 11th Screen Actors Guild Awards, James Garner was nominated for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Supporting Role and Gena Rowlands won Best Supporting Actress – Drama at the 9th Golden Satellite Awards.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Gran Via" />
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>29000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United States of America">
					<cities>South Carolina</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Nick Cassavetes</name>
				<biography>	
					Nicholas David Rowland Cassavetes (born May 21, 1959) is an American actor, director, and writer. He has directed such films as She's So Lovely (1997), John Q. (2002), The Notebook (2004), Alpha Dog (2006), and My Sister's Keeper (2009). His acting credits include an uncredited role in Husbands (1970)—which was directed by his father, John Cassavetes—as well as roles in the films The Wraith (1986), Face/Off (1997), and Blow (2001).
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Jeremy Leven</name>
				<biography>	
					Jeremy Leven (born August 16, 1941) is an American screenwriter, director, producer, and novelist. Born in South Bend, Indiana, Leven lives in Woodbridge, Connecticut, Paris, and New York City.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Mark Johnson</name>
				<biography>	
					Mark Johnson (born December 27, 1945) is an American film and television producer. He won the Academy Award for Best Picture for producing the 1988 film Rain Man.
				</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Aaron Zigman</name>
				<biography>	
					Aaron Zigman (born January 6, 1963) is a classically-trained American composer, producer, arranger, songwriter, and musician who has scored music for films including The Notebook, The Company Men, Bridge to Terabithia, John Q., The Proposal, Flicka, For Colored Girls, Flash of Genius, Sex and the City, Alpha Dog, and Escape from Planet Earth. He has also written, arranged and produced over 50 hit albums, and co-written songs with legendary and contemporary artists including Quincy Jones, Christina Aguilera, Phil Collins, Was (Not Was), John Legend, Dionne Warwick, Ray Charles, Natalie Cole, Aretha Franklin, Tina Turner, and Seal.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Ryan Gosling</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<other_works ID="ID-9" />
					<character>Noah Calhoun</character>
					<character_description>Noah Calhoun is the main protagonist of the 2004 film,The notebook. He's the boyfriend and later husband of 17 year-old Allie Hamilton.At a summer carnival in 1940,Noah saw Allie. He fell in love with the young lady and wanted to go on a date with her. So bad actually, that the dude was willing to risk his life for it.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Rachel McAdams</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Allie Hamilton</character>
					<character_description>Allison "Allie" Hamilton is a 17 year old rich girl in The Notebook (film). She soon falls in love with a poor boy Noah Calhoun. Allison's parents parents do not approve of him and later left town.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>James Garner</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Noah Calhoun</character>
					<character_description>Noah Calhoun is the main protagonist of the 2004 film,The notebook. He's the boyfriend and later husband of 17 year-old Allie Hamilton.At a summer carnival in 1940,Noah saw Allie. He fell in love with the young lady and wanted to go on a date with her. So bad actually, that the dude was willing to risk his life for it.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Gena Rowlands</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Allie Hamilton</character>
					<character_description>Allison "Allie" Hamilton is a 17 year old rich girl in The Notebook (film). She soon falls in love with a poor boy Noah Calhoun. Allison's parents parents do not approve of him and later left town.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>James Marsden</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Lon Hammond</character>
					<character_description>Lon Hammond, Jr. is Allie's fiancé; he's an intelligent and hardworking lawyer who comes from a wealthy, powerful family who made their money in the cotton industry long ago</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Jamie Anne Allmank</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Martha Shaw</character>
					<character_description>Martha Shaw is a war widow and Noah’s neighbor in New Bern. Noah regularly helps Martha, a single mother of three, with home repairs and small favors. In return, Martha often brings over homemade food and baked goods.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Justine Halliday</name>
				<biography>Justine Halliday is known for The Notebook (2004), One Hour Photo (2002) and Alpha Dog (2006).</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Claude Letessier</name>
				<biography>Letessier studied psycho-acoustics and political economy (PhD) before starting what would become the most important music production and sound design company in Europe: Vol de Nuit. In 1996, upon his invitation, he joined long time friend Hans Zimmer, to create a sound design division at Media Ventures in Santa Monica and collaborate with Hans on numerous major projects. Working with Terrence Malick on The Thin Red Line (1998) as a sound designer and an ethnomusicologist (Malick and Letessier produced a CD of the Solomon Islands Melanesian choirs: The Blessed Islands) and _Endurance (1998)_ certainly was the highlight of his career. Letessier has art directed soundscapes, created and composed sounds and sound design for some of the most prestigious and creative directors: Steven Spielberg, Marc Pellington, Tarsem, Wong-Kar Wai, Michael Bay, Wim Wenders, Terrence Malick to name a few.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Steven Gorel" />
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="New Line Cinema" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>3</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.8</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>54</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>117800000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
	</movie>
	<movie id="ID-11" title="John Wick 2" release_date="2017-01-30" duration="122" rating="PG-13">
		<genres>
			<genre type="Action" />
			<genre type="Thriller" />
		</genres>
		<plot>
				John Wick recovers his stolen Ford Mustang from Abram Tarasov, the late Viggo's brother. Wick dispatches Tarasov's men in a violent rampage that heavily damages the Mustang but spares Tarasov under the promise of peace and returns home. Wick has his Mustang taken for repairs by chop-shop owner Aurelio.
				John is visited by the Camorra crime boss Santino D'Antonio, who reminds him that he helped John complete his "impossible task," which allowed John to retire and marry Helen. In return, John swore to a "marker," an unbreakable vow symbolized by a "blood oath" medallion. Santino presents the marker to demand services from John, who declines, so Santino retaliates by destroying John's house with a grenade launcher. John survives and travels to the Continental Hotel in New York City, where Winston reminds him that if he rejects the marker, he will violate one of the underworld's two unbreakable rules: no killing on Continental grounds and honoring every marker. John reluctantly accepts his commitment and meets with Santino, who tasks him with assassinating his sister, Gianna, so that he can claim her seat at the "High Table," a council of twelve high-level crime bosses. Santino sends Ares, his mute bodyguard, to observe John's mission.
				In Rome, Italy, John infiltrates Gianna's coronation, confronting her in her dressing room. Faced with certain death, Gianna chooses to slit her wrists. As Gianna dies, John shoots her in the head to end her suffering and fulfill the marker. As John leaves, Gianna's bodyguard, Cassian, recognizes him, realizes that he was sent to kill Gianna, and attacks him. John flees to the catacombs, where he is double-crossed by Ares and Santino's henchmen, who intend to tie up "loose ends" by killing him. After killing most of the henchmen, John is again pursued by Cassian. Their fight leads them into the Rome Continental's reception area, where "conducting business" is strictly forbidden, like the New York Continental. As the two share a drink, John explains his reason for killing Gianna. Nevertheless, Cassian promises John a quick and clean death as a sign of professional respect.Julius, the Roman Continental's manager, arranges safe passage for John back to New York as Santino opens a contract for $7 million to kill John, ostensibly to avenge his sister's death. This leads numerous assassins to unsuccessfully attack John, during which Winston visits Santino to complete the marker, thus freeing John from being unable to move against him. Winston warns Santino that he "stabbed the devil in the back" and that he will be unprepared for John's wrath.
				Injured from numerous attempted assassinations, John is then confronted by Cassian in the subway. After a vicious fight culminating in Cassian being stabbed in the aorta, John spares him. The badly injured John seeks help from an underground crime boss known as the Bowery King, whose subordinates treat John's injuries. Intrigued by John's intent to kill a member of the High Table, the Bowery King sportingly gives him a Kimber M1911 pistol with only seven bullets, one for each million of the contract. He directs John to an art museum where Santino holds a gala. John pursues Santino throughout the museum, killing his remaining henchmen, including Ares, who gives Santino enough time to escape to the Continental, where he intends to remain indefinitely in its sanctuary. Despite Winston's warnings, the exasperated John shoots and kills Santino in the Continental lounge.
				The next day, Winston meets with John and explains that the Camorra has doubled the contract on John, offering it globally. Further, for "conducting business" on Continental grounds, per the High Table's rules, Winston is forced to declare John "excommunicado," terminating all his access and privileges to underworld resources. However, Winston delays activating John's excommunication by one hour (giving him a head start) and provides him with a marker for future use. Before leaving, John advises Winston to warn every other High Table assassin that he will kill anyone who tries to hunt him. John departs with his dog as Winston makes a call enacting John's "excommunicado" to be activated in one hour. As news of the imminent contract disseminates, cellular phones ring all around, and John begins to run.
		</plot>
		<production>
			<companies>
				<company name="Summit Entertainment" />
				<company name="TIK Films" />
				<company name="Thunder Road Pictures" />
				<company name="87Eleven Productions" />
			</companies>
			<budget>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>40000000</amount>
			</budget>
			<shooting_locations>
				<country name="United States of America">
					<cities>New York</cities>
				</country>
				<country name="Canada">
					<cities>Montreal</cities>
				</country>
			</shooting_locations>
		</production>
		<creative_team>
			<employee>
				<name>Chad Stahelski</name>
				<biography>	
					Chad Stahelski (born September 20, 1968) is an American stuntman and film director. He directed the 2014 film John Wick and its three sequels. He has worked as a stuntman, stunt coordinator and second unit director on several films.
				</biography>
				<job>Director</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-5" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Derek Kolstad</name>
				<biography>	
					Derek Kolstad (born April 4, 1974) is an American screenwriter and film producer. He is the creator of the John Wick franchise, which began in 2014. He continued to write for the first two sequels of the franchise and is mainly known as a screenwriter of action films and shows. Originally from Madison, Wisconsin, Kolstad attended Edgewood High School of the Sacred Heart and later studied business administration at Taylor University in Indiana. He moved to California at age 24 to pursue screenwriting. He says he started writing films when he was a teenager, but he struggled to find success in Hollywood at first.
				</biography>
				<job>Screenwriter</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-5" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Basil Iwanyk</name>
				<biography>	
					Basil William Iwanyk (born January 4, 1970) is an American film producer. He is the founder of Thunder Road Films and most known for Sicario, The Town, Greenland and the John Wick franchise. His films have earned more than $2 billion internationally as of 2018. He is of Ukrainian descent.After starting out working for Warner Bros in the 1990s, Basil founded his own company, Thunder Road, in 2000. The company has a stellar reputation within the industry and a remarkable track record of critical and commercial success.</biography>
				<job>Producer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-5" />
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Tyler Bates</name>
				<biography>	
					Tyler Bates (born June 5, 1965 is an American musician,producer, and composer for film, television, and video game scores.Much of his work is in the action and horror film genres, with films like Dawn of the Dead, 300, Sucker Punch, Halloween I and II, and the John Wick franchise. He has collaborated with directors like Zack Snyder, Rob Zombie, Neil Marshall, William Friedkin, Scott Derrickson, James Gunn, Chad Stahelski and David Leitch. In addition, he is also the former lead guitarist of the American rock band Marilyn Manson, and produced its albums The Pale Emperor and Heaven Upside Down. He's currently Jerry Cantrell‘s touring/studio member.
				</biography>
				<job>Composer</job>
				<other_works ID="ID-5" />
			</employee>
		</creative_team>
		<cast>
			<lead_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Keanu Reeves</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<other_works ID="ID-5" />
					<character>John Wick</character>
					<character_description>John Wick is a fictional character created by American screenwriter Derek Kolstad and portrayed by Canadian actor Keanu Reeves. He is the titular protagonist of the American media franchise John Wick. In the franchise's film series, he is introduced as a legendary Belarusian-American ex-hitman who left the criminal underworld after falling in love with and marrying a woman named Helen. While suffering from a terminal illness, Helen made arrangements for a puppy to be delivered to John in order to serve as his companion after her death. Days after her funeral, a Russian-American mobster — the son of John's former mafia boss — takes an interest in John's car after seeing it a gas station and is angered when John refuses to sell it to him. That night, he leads a group and breaks into John's house, assaulting him and killing his puppy before stealing his car. The attack sets John on a path of revenge, returning him to the violent lifestyle that he had left behind and eventually bringing him into conflict with the international organization of assassins of which he was once a part.</character_description>
					<role>Protagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Riccardo Scamarcio</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Santino D'Antonio</character>
					<character_description>Santino D'Antonio was an Italian crime boss formerly associated with John Wick. In order to retire from his assassin life, John asked for additional support from Santino in order to complete the "impossible task" given to him by his then employer Viggo Tarasov: forcing John to enter into a blood oath debt with Santino through a Marker.More than five years later, Santino forced John to honor the debt and commanded him to assassinate Santino's own sister, Gianna D'Antonio. John succeeds, thus making Santino the next head of the crime organization known as the Camorra, and consequently one of the twelve sitting members of the High Table.He serves as the main antagonist of John Wick: Chapter 2, and a posthumous antagonist of its sequel John Wick: Chapter 3 – Parabellum.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Ruby Rose</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Ares</character>
					<character_description>Ares was the alias of the mute right-hand woman for Italian crime lord Santino D'Antonio, for whom she worked as both an assassin and his personal bodyguard. She serves as the secondary antagonist of John Wick: Chapter 2.</character_description>
					<role>Antagonist</role>
				</employee>
			</lead_role>
			<support_role>
				<employee>
					<name>Ian McShane</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<other_works ID="ID-5 ID-6" />
					<character>Winston</character>
					<character_description>Winston Scott is the current owner and manager of the New York Continental Hotel, an establishment that functions as a neutral territory and safe zone for criminals and hired killers. No business is allowed to be conducted on Continental grounds, and those who violate this important rule are given severe penalties: which are often ordered and overseen by Winston himself. Although he is a close friend and ally of John Wick, he is still a high-ranking and powerful member of the Continental, and does what he has to do to those who break its rules.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
				<employee>
					<name>Franco Nero</name>
					<job>Actor</job>
					<character>Julius</character>
					<character_description>Just like Winston and any other manager/owner of a Continental Hotel, Julius takes his position very seriously and does everything to ensure that every assassin obeys to the rules in the criminal underworld, particularly no business allowed to be conducted inside the Continental's grounds. Much like Winston did with John Wick, Julius suggested to John and Cassian having some drinks to calm their nerves.</character_description>
					<role>Neutral</role>
				</employee>
			</support_role>
		</cast>
		<post_production>
			<employee>
				<name>Evan Schiff</name>
				<biography>Evan Schiff was born on 8 July 1982 in DeWitt, New York, USA. He is an editor, known for John Wick: Chapter 3 - Parabellum (2019), Sky Captain and the World of Tomorrow (2004) and Star Trek Into Darkness (2013).</biography>
				<job>Film Editor</job>
			</employee>
			<employee>
				<name>Alan Rankin</name>
				<biography>Alan Rankine (17 May 1958 – 2 January 2023) was a Scottish musician and record producer best known as keyboardist and guitarist for rock band the Associates, which he co-founded with lead vocalist Billy Mackenzie in the late 1970s.</biography>
				<job>Sound Designer</job>
			</employee>
			<publicity_company>
				<company name="Julie Fontaine" />
			</publicity_company>
		</post_production>
		<release_and_distribution>
			<distribution_company>
				<company name="Lionsgate" />
			</distribution_company>
		</release_and_distribution>
		<reception>
			<viewer_rating>4</viewer_rating>
			<IMDb>7.4</IMDb>
			<rotten_tomatoes>89</rotten_tomatoes>
			<revenue>
				<currency>Dollar</currency>
				<amount>174300000</amount>
			</revenue>
		</reception>
		<franchise>
			<prequels ID="ID-5" />
		</franchise>
	</movie>
</movies>